<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://www.mso.anu.edu.au/~murphysj/citation_summary.xsl" ?>
<records retrieved="35" citations="1178">
<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2018PASA...35...10W</bibcode>
<title>SkyMapper Southern Survey: First Data Release (DR1)</title>
<author>Wolf, Christian</author>
<author>Onken, Christopher A.</author>
<author>Luvaul, Lance C.</author>
<author>Schmidt, Brian P.</author>
<author>Bessell, Michael S.</author>
<author>Chang, Seo-Won</author>
<author>Da Costa, Gary S.</author>
<author>Mackey, Dougal</author>
<author>Martin-Jones, Tony</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Preston, Tim</author>
<author>Scalzo, Richard A.</author>
<author>Shao, Li</author>
<author>Smillie, Jon</author>
<author>Tisserand, Patrick</author>
<author>White, Marc C.</author>
<author>Yuan, Fang</author>
<affiliation>AA(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All-sky Astrophysics (CAASTRO)), AB(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All-sky Astrophysics (CAASTRO)), AC(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AD(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All-sky Astrophysics (CAASTRO)), AE(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AF(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All-sky Astrophysics (CAASTRO)), AG(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AH(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AI(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AJ(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; School of Physical, Environmental and Mathematical Sciences, University of New South Wales Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia), AK(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; Carolus Software Ltd., 244 5th Avenue, New York, NY 10001, USA), AL(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All-sky Astrophysics (CAASTRO); Centre for Translational Data Science, University of Sydney, NSW 2006, Australia 0000-0003-3740-1214), AM(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; Kavli Institute for Astronomy and Astrophysics, Peking University, 5 Yiheyuan Road, Haidian District, Beijing 100871, P. R. China 0000-0003-2015-777X), AN(National Computational Infrastructure, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2601, Australia), AO(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; Sorbonne Universités, UPMC Univ Paris 6 et CNRS, Institut d`Astrophysique de Paris, 98 bis bd Arago, F-75014 Paris, France), AP(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AQ(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All-sky Astrophysics (CAASTRO); Geoscience Australia, GPO Box 378, Canberra, ACT 2601, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>Publications of the Astronomical Society of Australia, Volume 35, id.e010 29 pp.</journal>
<volume>35</volume>
<pubdate>Feb 2018</pubdate>
<page>e010</page>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>catalogs</keyword>
<keyword>methods: observational</keyword>
<keyword>surveys</keyword>
<keyword>telescopes</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>CUP</origin>
<copyright>2018: Astronomical Society of Australia</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018PASA...35...10W&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018PASA...35...10W&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018PASA...35...10W&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018PASA...35...10W&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018PASA...35...10W&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>2</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018PASA...35...10W&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>61</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018PASA...35...10W&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>186</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018PASA...35...10W&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="ASSOCIATED">
  <name>Associated Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018PASA...35...10W&#38;link_type=ASSOCIATED</url>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018PASA...35...10W&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<link type="OPENURL">
  <name>Library Link Server</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018PASA...35...10W&#38;link_type=OPENURL</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2018PASA...35...10W</url>
<score>186.000</score>
<citations>186</citations>
<abstract>We present the first data release of the SkyMapper Southern Survey, a
hemispheric survey carried out with the SkyMapper Telescope at Siding
Spring Observatory in Australia. Here, we present the survey strategy,
data processing, catalogue construction, and database schema. The first
data release dataset includes over 66 000 images from the Shallow Survey
component, covering an area of 17 200 deg2 in all six
SkyMapper passbands uvgriz, while the full area covered by any passband
exceeds 20 000 deg2. The catalogues contain over 285 million
unique astrophysical objects, complete to roughly 18 mag in all bands.
We compare our griz point-source photometry with Pan-STARRS1 first data
release and note an RMS scatter of 2%. The internal reproducibility of
SkyMapper photometry is on the order of 1%. Astrometric precision is
better than 0.2 arcsec based on comparison with Gaia first data release.
We describe the end-user database, through which data are presented to
the world community, and provide some illustrative science queries.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1017/pasa.2018.5</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1801.07834</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2012PASP..124..140B</bibcode>
<title>Spectrophotometric Libraries, Revised Photonic Passbands, and Zero Points for UBVRI, Hipparcos, and Tycho Photometry</title>
<author>Bessell, Michael</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon</author>
<affiliation>AA(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Mount Stromlo Observatory, The Australian National University, ACT 2611, Australia; bessell@mso.anu.edu.au), AB(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Mount Stromlo Observatory, The Australian National University, ACT 2611, Australia; bessell@mso.anu.edu.au)</affiliation>
<journal>Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific, Volume 124, Issue 912, pp. 140 (2012).</journal>
<volume>124</volume>
<pubdate>Feb 2012</pubdate>
<page>140</page>
<lastpage></lastpage>
<origin>IOP</origin>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012PASP..124..140B&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012PASP..124..140B&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012PASP..124..140B&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012PASP..124..140B&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012PASP..124..140B&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>3</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012PASP..124..140B&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>56</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012PASP..124..140B&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>128</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012PASP..124..140B&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012PASP..124..140B&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>1</count>
</link>
<link type="ASSOCIATED">
  <name>Associated Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012PASP..124..140B&#38;link_type=ASSOCIATED</url>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012PASP..124..140B&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2012PASP..124..140B</url>
<score>128.000</score>
<citations>128</citations>
<abstract>We have calculated improved photonic passbands for the UBVRI, Hipparcos
Hp, and Tycho BT and VT standard
systems using the extensive spectrophotometric libraries of NGSL and
MILES. Using the Hp passband, we adjusted the absolute flux
levels of stars in the spectrophotometric libraries so that their
synthetic Hp magnitudes matched the precise Hipparcos
Catalogue value. Synthetic photometry based on the renormalized fluxes
was compared with the standard UBVRI, BT and VT
magnitudes, and revised synthetic zero points were determined. The
Hipparcos and Tycho photometry system zero points were also compared
with the V-magnitude zero points of the SAAO UBVRI system, the
homogenized UBV system, and the Walraven VB system. The confusion in the
literature concerning broadband magnitudes, fluxes, passbands, and the
choice of appropriate mean wavelengths is detailed and discussed in the
Appendix.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1086/664083</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1112.2698</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2013ApJ...774..101R</bibcode>
<title>The GALEX Nearby Young-Star Survey</title>
<author>Rodriguez, David R.</author>
<author>Zuckerman, B.</author>
<author>Kastner, Joel H.</author>
<author>Bessell, M. S.</author>
<author>Faherty, Jacqueline K.</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Departamento de Astronomía, Universidad de Chile, Casilla 36-D, Santiago, Chile drodrigu@das.uchile.cl), AB(Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of California, Los Angeles, CA 90095, USA), AC(Center for Imaging Science and Laboratory for Multiwavelength Astrophysics, Rochester Institute of Technology, 54 Lomb Memorial Drive, Rochester, NY 14623, USA), AD(The Australian National University, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia), AE(Departamento de Astronomía, Universidad de Chile, Casilla 36-D, Santiago, Chile; Department of Astrophysics, American Museum of Natural History, Central Park West at 79th Street, New York, NY 10034, USA), AF(The Australian National University, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia; Gliese Fellow, Astronomisches Rechen-Institut, Zentrum für Astronomie der Universität Heidelberg, D-69120 Heidelberg, Germany)</affiliation>
<journal>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 774, Issue 2, article id. 101, 22 pp. (2013).</journal>
<volume>774</volume>
<pubdate>Sep 2013</pubdate>
<page>101</page>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>open clusters and associations: individual: Tuc-Hor Columba</keyword>
<keyword>stars: evolution</keyword>
<keyword>stars: pre-main sequence</keyword>
<keyword>ultraviolet: stars</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>IOP</origin>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774..101R&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774..101R&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774..101R&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774..101R&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774..101R&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>92</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774..101R&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>87</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774..101R&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774..101R&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>113</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774..101R&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2013ApJ...774..101R</url>
<score>87.000</score>
<citations>87</citations>
<abstract>We describe a method that exploits data from the Galaxy Evolution
Explorer (GALEX) ultraviolet and Wide-field Infrared Survey Explorer and
Two Micron All Sky Survey infrared source catalogs, combined with proper
motions and empirical pre-main sequence isochrones, to identify
candidate nearby, young, low-mass stars. Applying our method across the
full GALEX-covered sky, we identify 2031 mostly M-type stars that, for
an assumed age of 10 (100) Myr, all lie within ~150 (~90) pc of Earth.
The distribution of M spectral subclasses among these ~2000 candidate
young stars peaks sharply in the range M3-M4; these subtypes constitute
50% of the sample, consistent with studies of the M star population in
the immediate solar neighborhood. We focus on a subset of 58 of these
candidate young M stars in the vicinity of the Tucana-Horologium
association. Only 20 of these 58 candidates were detected in the ROSAT
All-Sky X-ray Survey—reflecting the greater sensitivity of GALEX
for the purposes of identifying active nearby, young stars, particularly
for stars of type M4 and later. Based on statistical analysis of the
kinematics and/or spectroscopic followup of these 58 M stars, we find
that 50% (29 stars) indeed have properties consistent with Tuc-Hor
membership, while 12 are potential new members of the Columba
association, and 2 may be AB Dor moving group members. Hence, ~75% of
our initial subsample of 58 candidates are likely members of young (age
~ 10-40 Myr) stellar moving groups within 100 pc, verifying that the
stellar color- and kinematics-based selection algorithms described here
can be used to efficiently isolate nearby, young, low-mass objects from
among the field star population. Future studies will focus on
characterizing additional subsamples selected from among this list of
candidate nearby, young M stars.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1088/0004-637X/774/2/101</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1307.3262</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2008ApJ...678..851K</bibcode>
<title>Revealing Substructure in the Galactic Halo: The SEKBO RR Lyrae Survey</title>
<author>Keller, Stefan C.</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon</author>
<author>Prior, Sayuri</author>
<author>DaCosta, Gary</author>
<author>Schmidt, Brian</author>
<affiliation>AA(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, Australia), AB(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, Australia), AC(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, Australia), AD(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, Australia), AE(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 678, Issue 2, pp. 851-864 (2008).</journal>
<volume>678</volume>
<pubdate>May 2008</pubdate>
<page>851</page>
<lastpage>864</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>Galaxy: halo</keyword>
<keyword>Galaxy: structure</keyword>
<keyword>stars: variables: other</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>IOP</origin>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2008ApJ...678..851K&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2008ApJ...678..851K&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2008ApJ...678..851K&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2008ApJ...678..851K&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2008ApJ...678..851K&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>1</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2008ApJ...678..851K&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>61</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2008ApJ...678..851K&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>76</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2008ApJ...678..851K&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2008ApJ...678..851K&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>10</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2008ApJ...678..851K&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2008ApJ...678..851K</url>
<score>76.000</score>
<citations>76</citations>
<abstract>We present a search for RR Lyrae variable stars from archival
observations of the Southern Edgeworth-Kuiper Belt Object survey. The
survey covers 1675 deg2 along the ecliptic to a mean depth of
V = 19.5, i.e., a heliocentric distance of ~50 kpc for RR Lyrae stars.
The survey reveals 2016 RR Lyrae candidates. Follow-up photometric
monitoring of a subset of these candidates shows ~24% contamination by
non-RR Lyrae variables. We derive a map of overdensity of RR Lyrae stars
in the halo that reveals a series of structures coincident with the
leading and trailing arms of debris from the Sagittarius dwarf galaxy.
One of the regions of overdensity is found on the trailing arm, 200°
from the main body of the Sagittarius dwarf at a distance of ~45 kpc.
This distant detection of the stellar population of the outer trailing
arm of Sagittarius offers a tight constraint on the motion of the dwarf
galaxy. A distinctly separate region of overdensity is seen toward the
Virgo overdensity.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1086/526516</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:0711.2337</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2013MNRAS.435.1325M</bibcode>
<title>Re-examining the membership and origin of the ɛ Cha association</title>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Lawson, Warrick A.</author>
<author>Bessell, Michael S.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Gliese Fellow, Astronomisches Rechen-Institut, Zentrum für Astronomie der Universität Heidelberg, D-69120 Heidelberg, Germany; Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; murphy@ari.uni-heidelberg.de), AB(School of Physical, Environmental and Mathematical Sciences, University of New South Wales, Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia), AC(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 435, Issue 2, p.1325-1349</journal>
<volume>435</volume>
<pubdate>Oct 2013</pubdate>
<page>1325</page>
<lastpage>1349</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>stars: formation</keyword>
<keyword>stars: kinematics and dynamics</keyword>
<keyword>stars: low-mass</keyword>
<keyword>stars: pre-main sequence</keyword>
<keyword>open clusters and associations: individual: ɛ Chamaeleontis</keyword>
<keyword>η Chamaeleontis</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>OUP</origin>
<copyright>2013 The Authors Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Royal Astronomical Society</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013MNRAS.435.1325M&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013MNRAS.435.1325M&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013MNRAS.435.1325M&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013MNRAS.435.1325M&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013MNRAS.435.1325M&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>1</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013MNRAS.435.1325M&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>112</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013MNRAS.435.1325M&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>60</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013MNRAS.435.1325M&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013MNRAS.435.1325M&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>100</count>
</link>
<link type="ASSOCIATED">
  <name>Associated Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013MNRAS.435.1325M&#38;link_type=ASSOCIATED</url>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013MNRAS.435.1325M&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2013MNRAS.435.1325M</url>
<score>60.000</score>
<citations>60</citations>
<abstract>We present a comprehensive investigation of the ɛ Chamaeleontis
association (ɛ Cha), one of several young moving groups spread
across the southern sky. We re-assess the putative membership of
ɛ Cha using the best available proper motion and spectroscopic
measurements, including new ANU 2.3-m/Wide Field Spectrograph
observations. After applying a kinematic analysis, our final membership
comprises 35-41 stars from B9 to mid-M spectral types, with a mean
distance of 110 ± 7 pc and a mean space motion of (U, V, W) =
(-10.9 ± 0.8, -20.4 ± 1.3, -9.9 ± 1.4) km
s-1. Theoretical evolutionary models suggest ɛ Cha is
3-5 Myr old, distinguishing it as the youngest moving group in the solar
neighbourhood. 15 members show 3-22 μm spectral energy distributions
attributable to circumstellar discs, including 11 stars which appear to
be actively accreting. ɛ Cha's disc and accretion fractions
(29^{+8}_{-6} and 32^{+9}_{-7} per cent, respectively) are both
consistent with a typical 3-5 Myr old population. Multi-epoch
spectroscopy reveals three M-type members with broad and highly variable
Hα emission as well as several new spectroscopic binaries. We
reject 11 stars proposed as members in the literature and suggest they
may belong to the background Cha I and II clouds or other nearby young
groups. Our analysis underscores the importance of a holistic and
conservative approach to assigning young stars to kinematic groups, many
of which have only subtly different properties and ill-defined
memberships. We conclude with a brief discussion of ɛ Cha's
connection to the young open cluster η Cha and the
Scorpius-Centaurus OB association (Sco-Cen). Contrary to earlier studies
which assumed η and ɛ Cha are coeval and were born in the
same location, we find the groups were separated by ∼30 pc when
η Cha formed 4-8 Myr ago in the outskirts of Sco-Cen, 1-3 Myr before
the majority of ɛ Cha members.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnras/stt1375</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1305.4177</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2013ApJ...774...99K</bibcode>
<title>A High-resolution Spectroscopic Search for the Remaining Donor for Tycho's Supernova</title>
<author>Kerzendorf, Wolfgang E.</author>
<author>Yong, David</author>
<author>Schmidt, Brian P.</author>
<author>Simon, Joshua D.</author>
<author>Jeffery, C. Simon</author>
<author>Anderson, Jay</author>
<author>Podsiadlowski, Philipp</author>
<author>Gal-Yam, Avishay</author>
<author>Silverman, Jeffrey M.</author>
<author>Filippenko, Alexei V.</author>
<author>Nomoto, Ken'ichi</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Bessell, Michael S.</author>
<author>Venn, Kim A.</author>
<author>Foley, Ryan J.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Mount Stromlo Observatory, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia ; Department of Astronomy and Astrophysics, University of Toronto, 50 Saint George Street, Toronto, ON M5S 3H4, Canada; wkerzend@mso.anu.edu.au), AB(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Mount Stromlo Observatory, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia), AC(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Mount Stromlo Observatory, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia), AD(The Observatories of the Carnegie Institution for Science, 813 Santa Barbara Street, Pasadena, CA 91101, USA), AE(Armagh Observatory, College Hill, Armagh BT61 9DG, UK), AF(Space Telescope Science Institute, Baltimore, MD 21218, USA), AG(Department of Astrophysics, University of Oxford, Oxford, OX1 3RH, UK), AH(Benoziyo Center for Astrophysics, Faculty of Physics, The Weizmann Institute of Science, Rehovot 76100, Israel), AI(Department of Astronomy, University of California, Berkeley, CA 94720-3411, USA ; Department of Astronomy, University of Texas, Austin, TX 78712-0259, USA), AJ(Department of Astronomy, University of California, Berkeley, CA 94720-3411, USA), AK(Kavli Institute for the Physics and Mathematics of the Universe, The University of Tokyo, 5-1-5 Kashiwanoha, Kashiwa, Chiba 277-8583, Japan), AL(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Mount Stromlo Observatory, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia), AM(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Mount Stromlo Observatory, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia), AN(Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Victoria, Elliott Building, 3800 Finnerty Road, Victoria, BC V8P 5C2, Canada), AO(Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics, 60 Garden Street, Cambridge, MA 02138, USA)</affiliation>
<journal>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 774, Issue 2, article id. 99, 19 pp. (2013).</journal>
<volume>774</volume>
<pubdate>Sep 2013</pubdate>
<page>99</page>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>ISM: supernova remnants</keyword>
<keyword>supernovae: individual: SN1572 </keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>IOP</origin>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774...99K&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774...99K&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774...99K&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774...99K&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774...99K&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>2</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774...99K&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>91</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774...99K&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>59</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774...99K&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774...99K&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>28</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...774...99K&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2013ApJ...774...99K</url>
<score>59.000</score>
<citations>59</citations>
<abstract>In this paper, we report on our analysis using Hubble Space Telescope
astrometry and Keck-I HIRES spectroscopy of the central six stars of
Tycho's supernova remnant (SN 1572). With these data, we measured the
proper motions, radial velocities, rotational velocities, and chemical
abundances of these objects. Regarding the chemical abundances, we do
not confirm the unusually high [Ni/Fe] ratio previously reported for
Tycho-G. Rather, we find that for all metrics in all stars, none exhibit
the characteristics expected from traditional Type Ia supernova
single-degenerate-scenario calculations. The only possible exception is
Tycho-B, a rare, metal-poor A-type star; however, we are unable to find
a suitable scenario for it. Thus, we suggest that SN 1572 cannot be
explained by the standard single-degenerate model.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1088/0004-637X/774/2/99</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1210.2713</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2012Natur.487...74M</bibcode>
<title>Rapid disappearance of a warm, dusty circumstellar disk</title>
<author>Melis, Carl</author>
<author>Zuckerman, B.</author>
<author>Rhee, Joseph H.</author>
<author>Song, Inseok</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Bessell, Michael S.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Center for Astrophysics and Space Sciences, University of California, San Diego, California 92093-0424, USA; cmelis@ucsd.edu), AB(Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of California, Los Angeles, California 90095-1547, USA), AC(Department of Physics and Astronomy, California State Polytechnic University, Pomona, Pomona, California 91768, USA), AD(Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Georgia, Athens, Georgia 30602, USA), AE(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, College of Mathematical and Physical Sciences, The Australian National University, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, Australian Capital Territory 2611, Australia), AF(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, College of Mathematical and Physical Sciences, The Australian National University, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, Australian Capital Territory 2611, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>Nature, Volume 487, Issue 7405, pp. 74-76 (2012).</journal>
<volume>487</volume>
<pubdate>Jul 2012</pubdate>
<page>74</page>
<lastpage>76</lastpage>
<origin>NATURE</origin>
<copyright>(c) 2012: Nature Publishing Group, a division of Macmillan Publishers Limited. All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012Natur.487...74M&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012Natur.487...74M&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012Natur.487...74M&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012Natur.487...74M&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>2</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012Natur.487...74M&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>28</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012Natur.487...74M&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>59</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012Natur.487...74M&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012Natur.487...74M&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>7</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012Natur.487...74M&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<link type="OPENURL">
  <name>Library Link Server</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012Natur.487...74M&#38;link_type=OPENURL</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2012Natur.487...74M</url>
<score>59.000</score>
<citations>59</citations>
<abstract>Stars form with gaseous and dusty circumstellar envelopes, which rapidly
settle into disks that eventually give rise to planetary systems.
Understanding the process by which these disks evolve is paramount in
developing an accurate theory of planet formation that can account for
the variety of planetary systems discovered so far. The formation of
Earth-like planets through collisional accumulation of rocky objects
within a disk has mainly been explored in theoretical and computational
work in which post-collision ejecta evolution typically is ignored,
although recent work has considered the fate of such material. Here we
report observations of a young, Sun-like star (TYC 8241 2652 1) where
infrared flux from post-collisional ejecta has decreased drastically, by
a factor of about 30, over a period of less than two years. The star
seems to have gone from hosting substantial quantities of dusty ejecta,
in a region analogous to where the rocky planets orbit in the Solar
System, to retaining at most a meagre amount of cooler dust. Such a
phase of rapid ejecta evolution has not been previously predicted or
observed, and no currently available physical model satisfactorily
explains the observations.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1038/nature11210</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1207.1162</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2013ApJ...762...25N</bibcode>
<title>The Most Metal-poor Stars. I. Discovery, Data, and Atmospheric Parameters</title>
<author>Norris, John E.</author>
<author>Bessell, M. S.</author>
<author>Yong, David</author>
<author>Christlieb, N.</author>
<author>Barklem, P. S.</author>
<author>Asplund, M.</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Beers, Timothy C.</author>
<author>Frebel, Anna</author>
<author>Ryan, S. G.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Weston, ACT 2611, Australia jen@mso.anu.edu.au), AB(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Weston, ACT 2611, Australia bessell@mso.anu.edu.au), AC(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Weston, ACT 2611, Australia yong@mso.anu.edu.au), AD(Zentrum für Astronomie der Universität Heidelberg, Landessternwarte, Königstuhl 12, D-69117 Heidelberg, Germany martin@mso.anu.edu.au), AE(Department of Physics and Astronomy, Uppsala University, Box 515, SE-75120 Uppsala, Sweden n.christlieb@lsw.uni-heidelberg.de), AF(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Weston, ACT 2611, Australia; Max Planck Institute for Astrophysics, Postfach 1317, D-85741 Garching, Germany; paul.barklem@physics.uu.se), AG(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Weston, ACT 2611, Australia beers@pa.msu.edu), AH(National Optical Astronomy Observatory, Tucson, AZ 85719, USA ; Department of Physics and Astronomy and JINA: Joint Institute for Nuclear Astrophysics, Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI 48824, USA; afrebel@mit.edu), AI(Department of Physics, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA 02139, USA s.g.ryan@herts.ac.uk), AJ(Centre for Astrophysics Research, School of Physics, Astronomy and Mathematics, University of Hertfordshire, College Lane, Hatfield, Hertfordshire, AL10 9AB, UK)</affiliation>
<journal>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 762, Issue 1, article id. 25, 16 pp. (2013).</journal>
<volume>762</volume>
<pubdate>Jan 2013</pubdate>
<page>25</page>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>early universe</keyword>
<keyword>Galaxy: formation</keyword>
<keyword>Galaxy: halo</keyword>
<keyword>stars: abundances</keyword>
<keyword>stars: fundamental parameters</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>IOP</origin>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...762...25N&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...762...25N&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...762...25N&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...762...25N&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...762...25N&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>2</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...762...25N&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>77</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...762...25N&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>53</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...762...25N&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...762...25N&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>74</count>
</link>
<link type="ASSOCIATED">
  <name>Associated Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...762...25N&#38;link_type=ASSOCIATED</url>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...762...25N&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2013ApJ...762...25N</url>
<score>53.000</score>
<citations>53</citations>
<abstract>We report the discovery of 34 stars in the Hamburg/ESO Survey for
metal-poor stars and the Sloan Digital Sky Survey that have [Fe/H] &#60;~
-3.0. Their median and minimum abundances are [Fe/H] = -3.1
and -4.1, respectively, while 10 stars have [Fe/H] &#60;
-3.5. High-resolution, high signal-to-noise spectroscopic
data—equivalent widths and radial velocities—are presented
for these stars, together with an additional four objects previously
reported or currently being investigated elsewhere. We have determined
the atmospheric parameters, effective temperature (T eff),
and surface gravity (log g), which are critical in the determination of
the chemical abundances and the evolutionary status of these stars.
Three techniques were used to derive these parameters.
Spectrophotometric fits to model atmosphere fluxes were used to derive T
eff, log g, and an estimate of E(B - V); Hα,
Hβ, and Hγ profile fitting to model atmosphere results
provided the second determination of T eff and log g; and
finally, we used an empirical T eff-calibrated Hδ
index, for the third, independent T eff determination. The
three values of T eff are in good agreement, although the
profile fitting may yield systematically cooler T eff values,
by ~100 K. This collective data set will be analyzed in future papers in
the present series to utilize the most metal-poor stars as probes of
conditions in the early universe.

This paper includes data obtained with the ANU 2.3 m Telescope at
Siding Spring Observatory, Australia; the Magellan Clay Telescope at Las
Campanas Observatory, Chile; the Keck I Telescope at the W. M. Keck
Observatory, Hawaii, USA; and the VLT (Kueyen) of the European Southern
Observatory, Paranal, Chile (proposal 281.D-5015).</abstract>
<DOI>10.1088/0004-637X/762/1/25</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1208.2999</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2011AJ....142..104R</bibcode>
<title>The Solar Neighborhood. XXVI. AP Col: The Closest (8.4 pc) Pre-main-sequence Star</title>
<author>Riedel, Adric R.</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Henry, Todd J.</author>
<author>Melis, Carl</author>
<author>Jao, Wei-Chun</author>
<author>Subasavage, John P.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Department of Physics and Astronomy, Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA 30302-4106, USA ; Visiting Astronomer, Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory. CTIO is operated by AURA, Inc., under contract to the National Science Foundation.; riedel@chara.gsu.edu), AB(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia thenry@chara.gsu.edu), AC(Department of Physics and Astronomy, Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA 30302-4106, USA ; Visiting Astronomer, Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory. CTIO is operated by AURA, Inc., under contract to the National Science Foundation.; jao@chara.gsu.edu), AD(Center for Astrophysics and Space Sciences, University of California, San Diego, CA 92093-0424, USA murphysj@mso.anu.edu.au), AE(Department of Physics and Astronomy, Georgia State University, Atlanta, GA 30302-4106, USA ; Visiting Astronomer, Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory. CTIO is operated by AURA, Inc., under contract to the National Science Foundation.; cmelis@ucsd.edu), AF(Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory, La Serena, Chile ; Visiting Astronomer, Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory. CTIO is operated by AURA, Inc., under contract to the National Science Foundation.; jsubasavage@ctio.noao.edu)</affiliation>
<journal>The Astronomical Journal, Volume 142, Issue 4, article id. 104, 11 pp. (2011).</journal>
<volume>142</volume>
<pubdate>Oct 2011</pubdate>
<page>104</page>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>astrometry</keyword>
<keyword>parallaxes</keyword>
<keyword>solar neighborhood</keyword>
<keyword>stars: low-mass</keyword>
<keyword>stars: pre-main sequence</keyword>
<keyword>techniques: spectroscopic</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>IOP</origin>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011AJ....142..104R&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011AJ....142..104R&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011AJ....142..104R&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011AJ....142..104R&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011AJ....142..104R&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>71</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011AJ....142..104R&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>51</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011AJ....142..104R&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011AJ....142..104R&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>31</count>
</link>
<link type="ASSOCIATED">
  <name>Associated Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011AJ....142..104R&#38;link_type=ASSOCIATED</url>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011AJ....142..104R&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2011AJ....142..104R</url>
<score>51.000</score>
<citations>51</citations>
<abstract>We present the results of a multi-technique investigation of the M4.5Ve
flare star AP Col, which we discover to be the nearest pre-main-sequence
star. These include astrometric data from the CTIO 0.9 m, from which we
derive a proper motion of 342.0 ± 0.5 mas yr-1, a
trigonometric parallax of 119.21 ± 0.98 mas (8.39 ± 0.07
pc), and photometry and photometric variability at optical wavelengths.
We also provide spectroscopic data, including radial velocity (22.4
± 0.3 km s-1), lithium equivalent width (EW) (0.28
± 0.02 Å), Hα EW (-6.0 to -35 Å), vsin i (11
± 1 km s-1), and gravity indicators from the Siding
Spring 2.3 m WiFeS, Lick 3 m Hamilton echelle, and Keck-I HIRES echelle
spectrographs. The combined observations demonstrate that AP Col is the
closer of only two known systems within 10 pc of the Sun younger than
100 Myr. Given its space motion and apparent age of 12-50 Myr, AP Col is
likely a member of the recently proposed ~40 Myr old Argus/IC 2391
Association.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1088/0004-6256/142/4/104</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1108.5318</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2015MNRAS.447.1267M</bibcode>
<title>New low-mass members of the Octans stellar association and an updated 30-40 Myr lithium age</title>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Lawson, Warrick A.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Astronomisches Rechen-Institut, Zentrum für Astronomie der Universität Heidelberg, D-69120 Heidelberg, Germany; School of Physical, Environmental and Mathematical Sciences, University of New South Wales Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia murphy@ari.uni-heidelberg.de), AB(School of Physical, Environmental and Mathematical Sciences, University of New South Wales Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 447, Issue 2, p.1267-1281</journal>
<volume>447</volume>
<pubdate>Feb 2015</pubdate>
<page>1267</page>
<lastpage>1281</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>stars: kinematics and dynamics</keyword>
<keyword>stars: low-mass</keyword>
<keyword>stars: pre-main-sequence</keyword>
<keyword>open clusters and associations: individual: Octans</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>OUP</origin>
<copyright>2014 The Authors Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Royal Astronomical Society</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.447.1267M&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.447.1267M&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.447.1267M&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.447.1267M&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.447.1267M&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>2</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.447.1267M&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>75</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.447.1267M&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>39</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.447.1267M&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.447.1267M&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>59</count>
</link>
<link type="ASSOCIATED">
  <name>Associated Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.447.1267M&#38;link_type=ASSOCIATED</url>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.447.1267M&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2015MNRAS.447.1267M</url>
<score>39.000</score>
<citations>39</citations>
<abstract>The Octans association is one of several young stellar moving groups
recently discovered in the Solar neighbourhood and hence a valuable
laboratory for studies of stellar, circumstellar disc and planetary
evolution. However, a lack of low-mass members or any members with
trigonometric parallaxes means the age, distance and space motion of the
group are poorly constrained. To better determine its membership and
age, we present the first spectroscopic survey for new K- and M-type
Octans members, resulting in the discovery of 29 UV-bright K5-M4 stars
with kinematics, photometry and distances consistent with existing
members. Nine new members possess strong Li I λ6708 absorption,
which allow us to estimate a lithium age of 30-40 Myr, similar to that
of the Tucana-Horologium association and bracketed by the firm lithium
depletion boundary ages of the β Pictoris (20 Myr) and Argus/IC
2391 (50 Myr) associations. Several stars also show hints in our
medium-resolution spectra of fast rotation or spectroscopic binarity.
More so than other nearby associations, Octans is much larger than its
age and internal velocity dispersion imply. It may be the dispersing
remnant of a sparse, extended structure which includes some younger
members of the foreground Octans-Near association recently proposed by
Zuckerman and collaborators.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnras/stu2450</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1411.5703</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2009ApJ...691..306P</bibcode>
<title>Extending the Virgo Stellar Stream with SEKBO Survey RR Lyrae Stars</title>
<author>Prior, Sayuri L.</author>
<author>Da Costa, G. S.</author>
<author>Keller, Stefan C.</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AB(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AC(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AD(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 691, Issue 1, pp. 306-319 (2009).</journal>
<volume>691</volume>
<pubdate>Jan 2009</pubdate>
<page>306</page>
<lastpage>319</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>Galaxy: halo</keyword>
<keyword>Galaxy: kinematics and dynamics</keyword>
<keyword>Galaxy: structure</keyword>
<keyword>stars: variables: other</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>IOP</origin>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2009ApJ...691..306P&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2009ApJ...691..306P&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2009ApJ...691..306P&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2009ApJ...691..306P&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2009ApJ...691..306P&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>1</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2009ApJ...691..306P&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>41</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2009ApJ...691..306P&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>38</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2009ApJ...691..306P&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2009ApJ...691..306P&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>122</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2009ApJ...691..306P&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2009ApJ...691..306P</url>
<score>38.000</score>
<citations>38</citations>
<abstract>A subset of the RR Lyrae (RRL) candidates identified from the Southern
Edgeworth-Kuiper Belt Object (SEKBO) survey data have been followed up
photometrically (n = 106) and spectroscopically (n = 51). Period and
light curve fitting reveals a 24% ± 7% contamination of SEKBO
survey data by non-RRLs. This paper focuses on the region of the Virgo
Stellar Stream (VSS), particularly on its extension to the south of the
declination limits of the Sloan Digital Sky Survey and of the Quasar
Equatorial Survey Team RRL survey. The distribution of radial velocities
in the Galactic standard of rest frame (V GSR) for the 11
RRLs observed in the VSS region has two apparent peaks. The larger peak
coincides with the four RRLs having langV GSRrang = 127
± 10 km s-1 and dispersion σ = 27 km
s-1, marginally larger than that expected from the errors
alone. The two type ab RRLs in this group have lang[Fe/H]rang = -1.95
± 0.1. Both the radial velocities and metal abundances are
consistent with membership in the VSS. The second velocity peak, which
occurs at langV GSRrang = -175 ± 10 km s-1
may indicate the presence of stars from the Sgr leading tidal tail,
which is expected to have large negative velocities in this region. We
explore the spatial extent of the VSS by constructing luminosity
functions from the SEKBO data and comparing them to data synthesized
with the Besançon Galactic model. Analysis of the excess over the
model predictions reveals the VSS as a large (~760 deg2)
overdensity centered at roughly (R.A., decl.) ~ (186°, -4°),
spanning a length of ~15 kpc in projection, assuming a heliocentric
distance of 19 kpc. The data reveal for the first time the more southern
regions of the stream and trace it to decl. ≈-15° and Galactic
latitudes as low as b ≈ 45°.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1088/0004-637X/691/1/306</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:0810.0057</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2016PASA...33...55C</bibcode>
<title>The ANU WiFeS SuperNovA Programme (AWSNAP)</title>
<author>Childress, Michael J.</author>
<author>Tucker, Brad E.</author>
<author>Yuan, Fang</author>
<author>Scalzo, Richard</author>
<author>Ruiter, Ashley</author>
<author>Seitenzahl, Ivo</author>
<author>Zhang, Bonnie</author>
<author>Schmidt, Brian</author>
<author>Anguiano, Borja</author>
<author>Aniyan, Suryashree</author>
<author>Bayliss, Daniel D. R.</author>
<author>Bento, Joao</author>
<author>Bessell, Michael</author>
<author>Bian, Fuyan</author>
<author>Davies, Rebecca</author>
<author>Dopita, Michael</author>
<author>Fogarty, Lisa</author>
<author>Fraser-McKelvie, Amelia</author>
<author>Freeman, Ken</author>
<author>Kuruwita, Rajika</author>
<author>Medling, Anne M.</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Owers, Matthew</author>
<author>Panther, Fiona</author>
<author>Sweet, Sarah M.</author>
<author>Thomas, Adam D.</author>
<author>Zhou, George</author>
<affiliation>AA(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All-sky Astrophysics (CAASTRO), Canberra, ACT, Australia; School of Physics and Astronomy, University of Southampton, Southampton, SO17 1BJ, UK 0000-0003-1761-6533), AB(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All-sky Astrophysics (CAASTRO), Canberra, ACT, Australia), AC(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All-sky Astrophysics (CAASTRO), Canberra, ACT, Australia), AD(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AE(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All-sky Astrophysics (CAASTRO), Canberra, ACT, Australia), AF(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All-sky Astrophysics (CAASTRO), Canberra, ACT, Australia), AG(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AH(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AI(Department of Physics and Astronomy, Macquarie University, NSW 2109, Australia), AJ(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AK(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; Observatoire Astronomique de l'Université de Genève, 51 ch. des Maillettes, 1290 Versoix, Switzerland), AL(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AM(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AN(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AO(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AP(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AQ(Sydney Institute for Astronomy (SIfA), School of Physics, The University of Sydney, NSW 2006, Australia), AR(School of Physics and Astronomy, Monash University, Clayton, Victoria 3800, Australia; Monash Centre for Astrophysics (MoCA), Monash University, Clayton, Victoria 3800, Australia), AS(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AT(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AU(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AV(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AW(Sydney Institute for Astronomy (SIfA), School of Physics, The University of Sydney, NSW 2006, Australia; Stellar Astrophysics Centre, Department of Physics and Astronomy, Aarhus University, 8000 Aarhus C, Denmark), AX(Department of Physics and Astronomy, Macquarie University, NSW 2109, Australia; Australian Astronomical Observatory, PO Box 915, North Ryde, NSW 1670, Australia), AY(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All-sky Astrophysics (CAASTRO), Canberra, ACT, Australia), AZ(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), BA(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), BB(Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics, 60 Garden St, Cambridge, MA 02138, USA; Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>Publications of the Astronomical Society of Australia, Volume 33, id.e055 29 pp.</journal>
<volume>33</volume>
<pubdate>Nov 2016</pubdate>
<page>e055</page>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>supernovae: general</keyword>
<keyword>supernovae: individual: (SN 2012dn)</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>CUP</origin>
<copyright>2016: Astronomical Society of Australia</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016PASA...33...55C&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016PASA...33...55C&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016PASA...33...55C&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016PASA...33...55C&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016PASA...33...55C&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>120</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016PASA...33...55C&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>28</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016PASA...33...55C&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016PASA...33...55C&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<link type="OPENURL">
  <name>Library Link Server</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016PASA...33...55C&#38;link_type=OPENURL</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2016PASA...33...55C</url>
<score>28.000</score>
<citations>28</citations>
<abstract>This paper presents the first major data release and survey description
for the ANU WiFeS SuperNovA Programme. ANU WiFeS SuperNovA Programme is
an ongoing supernova spectroscopy campaign utilising the Wide Field
Spectrograph on the Australian National University 2.3-m telescope. The
first and primary data release of this programme (AWSNAP-DR1) releases
357 spectra of 175 unique objects collected over 82 equivalent full
nights of observing from 2012 July to 2015 August. These spectra have
been made publicly available via the WISEREP supernova spectroscopy
repository.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1017/pasa.2016.47</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1607.08526</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2010MNRAS.406L..50M</bibcode>
<title>First detection of a low-mass stellar halo around the young open cluster η Chamaeleontis</title>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Lawson, Warrick A.</author>
<author>Bessell, Michael S.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia), AB(School of PEMS, University of New South Wales, Australian Defence Force Academy, Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia), AC(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society: Letters, Volume 406, Issue 1, pp. L50-L54.</journal>
<volume>406</volume>
<pubdate>Jul 2010</pubdate>
<page>L50</page>
<lastpage>L54</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>stars: pre-main sequence</keyword>
<keyword>stars: kinematics and dynamics</keyword>
<keyword>open clusters and associations: individual: η Chamaeleontis</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>WILEY</origin>
<copyright>(c) Journal compilation © 2010 RAS</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2010MNRAS.406L..50M&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2010MNRAS.406L..50M&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2010MNRAS.406L..50M&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2010MNRAS.406L..50M&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2010MNRAS.406L..50M&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>18</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2010MNRAS.406L..50M&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>28</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2010MNRAS.406L..50M&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2010MNRAS.406L..50M&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>14</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2010MNRAS.406L..50M&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2010MNRAS.406L..50M</url>
<score>28.000</score>
<citations>28</citations>
<abstract>We have identified several lithium-rich low-mass (0.08 &#60; M &#60; 0.3
Msolar) stars within 5.5° of the young open cluster η
Chamaeleontis, nearly four times the radius of previous search efforts.
Of these stars, we propose four new probable cluster members and three
possible members requiring further investigation. These findings are
consistent with a dynamical origin for the current configuration of the
cluster, without the need to invoke an abnormal initial mass function
deficient in low-mass objects. Candidates were selected on the basis of
DENIS and Two-Micron All-Sky Survey photometry, Naval Observatory Merged
Astrometric Catalogue astrometry and extensive follow-up spectroscopy.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1111/j.1745-3933.2010.00879.x</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1005.3308</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2019MNRAS.488L.109N</bibcode>
<title>The lowest detected stellar Fe abundance: the halo star SMSS J160540.18-144323.1</title>
<author>Nordlander, T.</author>
<author>Bessell, M. S.</author>
<author>Da Costa, G. S.</author>
<author>Mackey, A. D.</author>
<author>Asplund, M.</author>
<author>Casey, A. R.</author>
<author>Chiti, A.</author>
<author>Ezzeddine, R.</author>
<author>Frebel, A.</author>
<author>Lind, K.</author>
<author>Marino, A. F.</author>
<author>Murphy, S. J.</author>
<author>Norris, J. E.</author>
<author>Schmidt, B. P.</author>
<author>Yong, D.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All Sky Astrophysics in 3 Dimensions (ASTRO 3D), Australia 0000-0001-5344-8069), AB(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All Sky Astrophysics in 3 Dimensions (ASTRO 3D), Australia 0000-0001-7801-1410), AC(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia 0000-0001-7019-649X), AD(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All Sky Astrophysics in 3 Dimensions (ASTRO 3D), Australia 0000-0002-6529-8093), AE(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All Sky Astrophysics in 3 Dimensions (ASTRO 3D), Australia 0000-0002-5804-3682), AF(School of Physics &#38; Astronomy, Monash University, Clayton, VIC 3800, Australia; Faculty of Information Technology, Monash University, Clayton, VIC 3800, Australia 0000-0003-0174-0564), AG(Department of Physics &#38; Kavli Institute for Astrophysics and Space Research, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA 02139, USA), AH(Department of Physics &#38; Kavli Institute for Astrophysics and Space Research, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA 02139, USA; Joint Institute for Nuclear Astrophysics - Center for Evolution of the Elements, East Lansing, MI 48824, USA), AI(Department of Physics &#38; Kavli Institute for Astrophysics and Space Research, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA 02139, USA; Joint Institute for Nuclear Astrophysics - Center for Evolution of the Elements, East Lansing, MI 48824, USA 0000-0002-2139-7145), AJ(Max-Planck-Institut für Astronomie, Königstuhl 17, D-69117 Heidelberg, Germany; Observational Astrophysics, Department of Physics and Astronomy, Uppsala University, Box 516, SE-75120 Uppsala, Sweden), AK(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia Galileo Galilei, Univ. di Padova, Vicolo dellOsservatorio 3, Padova I-35122, Italy 0000-0002-1276-5487), AL(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; School of Science, University of New South Wales, Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia 0000-0003-4932-7699), AM(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AN(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia 0000-0001-6589-1287), AO(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for All Sky Astrophysics in 3 Dimensions (ASTRO 3D), Australia 0000-0002-6502-1406)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society: Letters, Volume 488, Issue 1, p.L109-L113</journal>
<volume>488</volume>
<pubdate>Sep 2019</pubdate>
<page>L109</page>
<lastpage>L113</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>stars: abundances</keyword>
<keyword>stars: individual: SMSS J160540.18-144323.1</keyword>
<keyword>stars: Population III</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>OUP</origin>
<copyright>2019 The Author(s) Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Royal Astronomical Society</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.488L.109N&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.488L.109N&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.488L.109N&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.488L.109N&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.488L.109N&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>61</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.488L.109N&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>25</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.488L.109N&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.488L.109N&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>6</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.488L.109N&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<link type="OPENURL">
  <name>Library Link Server</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.488L.109N&#38;link_type=OPENURL</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2019MNRAS.488L.109N</url>
<score>25.000</score>
<citations>25</citations>
<abstract>We report the discovery of SMSS J160540.18-144323.1, a new ultra
metal-poor halo star discovered with the SkyMapper telescope. We measure
[{Fe}/{H}]= -6.2 ± 0.2 (1D LTE), the lowest ever detected
abundance of iron in a star. The star is strongly carbon-enhanced,
[{C}/{Fe}] = 3.9 ± 0.2, while other abundances are compatible
with an α-enhanced solar-like pattern with [{Ca}/{Fe}] = 0.4
± 0.2, [{Mg}/{Fe}] = 0.6 ± 0.2, [{Ti}/{Fe}] = 0.8 ±
0.2, and no significant s- or r-process enrichment, [{Sr}/{Fe}] &#60; 0.2
and [{Ba}/{Fe}] &#60; 1.0 (3σ limits). Population III stars
exploding as fallback supernovae may explain both the strong carbon
enhancement and the apparent lack of enhancement of odd-Z and
neutron-capture element abundances. Grids of supernova models computed
for metal-free progenitor stars yield good matches for stars of about 10
M_⊙ imparting a low kinetic energy on the supernova ejecta, while
models for stars more massive than roughly 20 M_⊙ are incompatible
with the observed abundance pattern.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnrasl/slz109</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1904.07471</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2015MNRAS.451.2263Z</bibcode>
<title>A 0.24+0.18 M⊙ double-lined eclipsing binary from the HATSouth survey</title>
<author>Zhou, G.</author>
<author>Bayliss, D.</author>
<author>Hartman, J. D.</author>
<author>Rabus, M.</author>
<author>Bakos, G. Á.</author>
<author>Jordán, A.</author>
<author>Brahm, R.</author>
<author>Penev, K.</author>
<author>Csubry, Z.</author>
<author>Mancini, L.</author>
<author>Espinoza, N.</author>
<author>de Val-Borro, M.</author>
<author>Bhatti, W.</author>
<author>Ciceri, S.</author>
<author>Henning, T.</author>
<author>Schmidt, B.</author>
<author>Murphy, S. J.</author>
<author>Butler, R. P.</author>
<author>Arriagada, P.</author>
<author>Shectman, S.</author>
<author>Crane, J.</author>
<author>Thompson, I.</author>
<author>Suc, V.</author>
<author>Noyes, R. W.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia george.zhou@anu.edu.au), AB(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AC(Department of Astrophysical Sciences, Princeton University, NJ 08544, USA), AD(Instituto de Astrofísica, Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile, Av. Vicuña Mackenna 4860, 7820436 Macul, Santiago, Chile; Max Planck Institute for Astronomy, Königstuhl 17, D-69117 Heidelberg, Germany), AE(Department of Astrophysical Sciences, Princeton University, NJ 08544, USA; ), AF(Instituto de Astrofísica, Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile, Av. Vicuña Mackenna 4860, 7820436 Macul, Santiago, Chile), AG(Instituto de Astrofísica, Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile, Av. Vicuña Mackenna 4860, 7820436 Macul, Santiago, Chile), AH(Department of Astrophysical Sciences, Princeton University, NJ 08544, USA), AI(Department of Astrophysical Sciences, Princeton University, NJ 08544, USA), AJ(Max Planck Institute for Astronomy, Königstuhl 17, D-69117 Heidelberg, Germany), AK(Instituto de Astrofísica, Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile, Av. Vicuña Mackenna 4860, 7820436 Macul, Santiago, Chile), AL(Department of Astrophysical Sciences, Princeton University, NJ 08544, USA), AM(Department of Astrophysical Sciences, Princeton University, NJ 08544, USA), AN(Max Planck Institute for Astronomy, Königstuhl 17, D-69117 Heidelberg, Germany), AO(Max Planck Institute for Astronomy, Königstuhl 17, D-69117 Heidelberg, Germany), AP(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AQ(Astronomisches Rechen-Institut, Zentrum für Astronomie der Universität Heidelberg, D-69120 Heidelberg, Germany), AR(Department of Terrestrial Magnetism, Carnegie Institution of Washington, 5241 Broad Branch Road NW, Washington, DC 20015-1305, USA), AS(Department of Terrestrial Magnetism, Carnegie Institution of Washington, 5241 Broad Branch Road NW, Washington, DC 20015-1305, USA), AT(The Observatories of the Carnegie Institution of Washington, 813 Santa Barbara Street, Pasadena, CA 91101, USA), AU(The Observatories of the Carnegie Institution of Washington, 813 Santa Barbara Street, Pasadena, CA 91101, USA), AV(The Observatories of the Carnegie Institution of Washington, 813 Santa Barbara Street, Pasadena, CA 91101, USA), AW(Instituto de Astrofísica, Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile, Av. Vicuña Mackenna 4860, 7820436 Macul, Santiago, Chile), AX(Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics, 60 Garden St, Cambridge, MA 02138, USA)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 451, Issue 3, p.2263-2277</journal>
<volume>451</volume>
<pubdate>Aug 2015</pubdate>
<page>2263</page>
<lastpage>2277</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>binaries: eclipsing</keyword>
<keyword>stars: individual: HATS551-027</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>OUP</origin>
<copyright>2015 The Authors Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Royal Astronomical Society</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.451.2263Z&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.451.2263Z&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.451.2263Z&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.451.2263Z&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.451.2263Z&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>2</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.451.2263Z&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>73</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.451.2263Z&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>25</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.451.2263Z&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.451.2263Z&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>12</count>
</link>
<link type="ASSOCIATED">
  <name>Associated Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.451.2263Z&#38;link_type=ASSOCIATED</url>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.451.2263Z&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2015MNRAS.451.2263Z</url>
<score>25.000</score>
<citations>25</citations>
<abstract>We report the discovery and characterization of a new M-dwarf binary,
with component masses and radii of M_1 = 0.244_{-0.003}^{+0.003}
M_{⊙}, R_1 = 0.261_{-0.009}^{+0.006} R_{⊙}, M_2 =
0.179_{-0.001}^{+0.002} M_{⊙}, R_2 = 0.218 _{-0.011}^{+0.007}
R_{⊙}, and orbital period of ∼4.1 d. The M-dwarf binary
HATS551-027 (LP 837-20) was identified as an eclipsing binary by the
HATSouth survey, and characterized by a series of high-precision
photometric observations of the eclipse events, and spectroscopic
determinations of the atmospheric parameters and radial velocity orbits.
HATS551-027 is one of few systems with both stellar components lying in
the fully convective regime of very low mass stars, and can serve as a
test for stellar interior models. The radius of HATS551-027A is
consistent with models to 1σ, whilst HATS551-027B is inflated by 9
per cent at 2σ significance. We measure the effective temperatures
for the two stellar components to be Teff, 1 = 3190 ±
100 K and Teff, 2 = 2990 ± 110 K; both are slightly
cooler than theoretical models predict, but consistent with other
M-dwarfs of similar masses that have previously been studied. We also
measure significant H α emission from both components of the
binary system, and discuss this in the context of the correlation
between stellar activity and the discrepancies between the observed and
model temperatures.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnras/stv1070</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1505.02860</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2018MNRAS.476.3290M</bibcode>
<title>WISE J080822.18-644357.3 - a 45 Myr-old accreting M dwarf hosting a primordial disc</title>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Mamajek, Eric E.</author>
<author>Bell, Cameron P. M.</author>
<affiliation>AA(School of Physical, Environmental and Mathematical Sciences, University of New South Wales Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia 0000-0003-4932-7699), AB(Jet Propulsion Laboratory, California Institute of Technology, 4800 Oak Grove Dr., Pasadena, CA 91109, USA; Department of Physics &#38; Astronomy, University of Rochester, Rochester, NY 14627, USA), AC(Leibniz Institute for Astrophysics Potsdam (AIP), An der Sternwarte 16, D-14482 Potsdam, Germany)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 476, Issue 3, p.3290-3302</journal>
<volume>476</volume>
<pubdate>May 2018</pubdate>
<page>3290</page>
<lastpage>3302</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>stars: fundamental parameters</keyword>
<keyword>stars: kinematics and dynamics</keyword>
<keyword>stars: pre-main-sequence</keyword>
<keyword>open clusters and associations: individual: Carina</keyword>
<keyword>solar neighbourhood</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>OUP</origin>
<copyright>2018 The Author(s) Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Royal Astronomical Society</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018MNRAS.476.3290M&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018MNRAS.476.3290M&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018MNRAS.476.3290M&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018MNRAS.476.3290M&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018MNRAS.476.3290M&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>1</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018MNRAS.476.3290M&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>139</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018MNRAS.476.3290M&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>24</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018MNRAS.476.3290M&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018MNRAS.476.3290M&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>47</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018MNRAS.476.3290M&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<link type="OPENURL">
  <name>Library Link Server</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2018MNRAS.476.3290M&#38;link_type=OPENURL</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2018MNRAS.476.3290M</url>
<score>24.000</score>
<citations>24</citations>
<abstract>WISE J080822.18-644357.3 (WISE J0808-6443) was recently identified as a
new M dwarf debris disc system and a candidate member of the 45 Myr-old
Carina association. Given that the strength of its infrared excess
(LIR/L⋆ ≃ 0.1) appears to be more
consistent with a young protoplanetary disc, we present the first
optical spectra of the star and reassess its evolutionary and membership
status. We find WISE J0808-6443 to be a Li-rich M5 star with strong H
α emission (-125 &#60; EW &#60; -65 Å over 4 epochs) whose
strength and broad width are consistent with accretion at a low level
(∼10-10 M⊙ yr-1) from its disc.
The spectral energy distribution of the star is consistent with a
primordial disc and is well-fitted using a two-temperature blackbody
model with Tinner ≃ 1100 K and Touter ≃
240 K. AllWISE multi-epoch photometry shows the system exhibits
significant variability in the 3.4 and 4.6 μm bands. We calculate an
improved proper motion based on archival astrometry, and combined with a
new radial velocity, the kinematics of the star are consistent with
membership in Carina at a kinematic distance of 90 ± 9 pc. The
spectroscopic and photometric data are consistent with WISE J0808-6443
being a ∼0.1 M⊙ Classical T-Tauri star and one of the
oldest known accreting M-type stars. These results provide further
evidence that the upper limit on the lifetimes of gas-rich discs - and
hence the time-scales to form and evolve protoplanetary systems - around
the lowest mass stars may be longer than previously recognized, or some
mechanism may be responsible for regenerating short-lived discs at later
stages of pre-main sequence evolution.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnras/sty471</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1703.04544</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2013ApJ...778...12M</bibcode>
<title>Copious Amounts of Hot and Cold Dust Orbiting the Main Sequence A-type Stars HD 131488 and HD 121191</title>
<author>Melis, Carl</author>
<author>Zuckerman, B.</author>
<author>Rhee, Joseph H.</author>
<author>Song, Inseok</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Bessell, Michael S.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Center for Astrophysics and Space Sciences, University of California, San Diego, CA 92093-0424, USA ; Joint NSF AAPF Fellow and CASS Postdoctoral Fellow.; cmelis@ucsd.edu), AB(Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of California, Los Angeles, CA 90095-1547, USA), AC(Department of Physics and Astronomy, California State Polytechnic University, Pomona, 3801 West Temple Avenue, Pomona, CA 91768, USA), AD(Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Georgia, Athens, GA 30602-2451, USA), AE(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia ; Current address: Astronomisches Rechen-Institut, Zentrum für Astronomie der Universität Heidelberg, D-69120 Heidelberg, Germany. ; Gliese Fellow.), AF(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 778, Issue 1, article id. 12, 8 pp. (2013).</journal>
<volume>778</volume>
<pubdate>Nov 2013</pubdate>
<page>12</page>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>circumstellar matter</keyword>
<keyword>infrared: planetary systems</keyword>
<keyword>planets and satellites: formation</keyword>
<keyword>stars: individual: HD 131488 HD 121191</keyword>
<keyword>stars: kinematics and dynamics</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>IOP</origin>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...778...12M&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...778...12M&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...778...12M&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...778...12M&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...778...12M&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>1</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...778...12M&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>64</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...778...12M&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>24</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...778...12M&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...778...12M&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>21</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2013ApJ...778...12M&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2013ApJ...778...12M</url>
<score>24.000</score>
<citations>24</citations>
<abstract>We report two new dramatically dusty main sequence stars: HD 131488 (A1
V) and HD 121191 (A8 V). HD 131488 is found to have substantial amounts
of dust in its terrestrial planet zone (L IR/L bol
≈ 4 × 10-3), cooler dust farther out in its
planetary system, and an unusual mid-infrared spectral feature. HD
121191 shows terrestrial planet zone dust (L IR/L
bol ≈ 2.3 × 10-3), hints of cooler
dust, and shares the unusual mid-infrared spectral shape identified in
HD 131488. These two stars belong to sub-groups of the
Scorpius-Centaurus OB association and have ages of ~10 Myr. HD 131488
and HD 121191 are the dustiest main sequence A-type stars currently
known. Early-type stars that host substantial inner planetary system
dust are thus far found only within the age range of 5-20 Myr.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1088/0004-637X/778/1/12</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1308.2753</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2019MNRAS.489.5900D</bibcode>
<title>The SkyMapper DR1.1 search for extremely metal-poor stars</title>
<author>Da Costa, G. S.</author>
<author>Bessell, M. S.</author>
<author>Mackey, A. D.</author>
<author>Nordlander, T.</author>
<author>Asplund, M.</author>
<author>Casey, A. R.</author>
<author>Frebel, A.</author>
<author>Lind, K.</author>
<author>Marino, A. F.</author>
<author>Murphy, S. J.</author>
<author>Norris, J. E.</author>
<author>Schmidt, B. P.</author>
<author>Yong, D.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 0200, Australia 0000-0001-7019-649X), AB(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 0200, Australia), AC(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 0200, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for Astrophysics in Three Dimensions (ASTRO-3D), Australia), AD(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 0200, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for Astrophysics in Three Dimensions (ASTRO-3D), Australia 0000-0001-5344-8069), AE(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 0200, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for Astrophysics in Three Dimensions (ASTRO-3D), Australia), AF(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 0200, Australia; School of Physics and Astronomy, Monash University, Wellington Rd, Clayton, VIC 3800, Australia; Faculty of Information Technology, Monash University, Wellington Rd, Clayton, VIC 3800, Australia 0000-0003-0174-0564), AG(Department of Physics and Kavli Institute for Astrophysics and Space Research, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA 02139, USA), AH(Max-Planck-Institut für Astronomie, Königstuhl 17, D-69117 Heidelberg, Germany; Observational Astrophysics, Department of Physics and Astronomy, Uppsala University, Box 516, SE-751 20 Uppsala, Sweden), AI(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 0200, Australia; Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia Galileo Galilei, Università di Padova, Vicolo dell'Osservatorio 3, I-35122 Padova, Italy; Centro di Ateneo di Studi e Attivita Spaziali `Giuseppe Colombo' - CISAS, Via Venezia 15, I-35131 Padova, Italy 0000-0002-1276-5487), AJ(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 0200, Australia; School of Science, University of New South Wales, Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia 0000-0003-4932-7699), AK(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 0200, Australia), AL(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 0200, Australia), AM(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 0200, Australia; ARC Centre of Excellence for Astrophysics in Three Dimensions (ASTRO-3D), Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 489, Issue 4, p.5900-5918</journal>
<volume>489</volume>
<pubdate>Nov 2019</pubdate>
<page>5900</page>
<lastpage>5918</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>stars: abundances</keyword>
<keyword>stars: Population II</keyword>
<keyword>Galaxy: halo</keyword>
<keyword>Galaxy: stellar content</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>OUP</origin>
<copyright>2019 The Author(s) Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Royal Astronomical Society</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.489.5900D&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.489.5900D&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.489.5900D&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.489.5900D&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.489.5900D&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>1</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.489.5900D&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>77</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.489.5900D&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>22</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.489.5900D&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.489.5900D&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>41</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.489.5900D&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<link type="OPENURL">
  <name>Library Link Server</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.489.5900D&#38;link_type=OPENURL</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2019MNRAS.489.5900D</url>
<score>22.000</score>
<citations>22</citations>
<abstract>We present and discuss the results of a search for extremely metal-poor
stars based on photometry from data release DR1.1 of the SkyMapper
imaging survey of the southern sky. In particular, we outline our
photometric selection procedures and describe the low-resolution (R ≈
3000) spectroscopic follow-up observations that are used to provide
estimates of effective temperature, surface gravity, and metallicity
([Fe/H]) for the candidates. The selection process is very efficient: of
the 2618 candidates with low-resolution spectra that have photometric
metallicity estimates less than or equal to -2.0, 41 per cent have
[Fe/H] ≤ -2.75 and only approximately seven per cent have [Fe/H] &#62;
-2.0 dex. The most metal-poor candidate in the sample has [Fe/H] &#60;
-4.75 and is notably carbon rich. Except at the lowest metallicities
([Fe/H] &#60; -4), the stars observed spectroscopically are dominated by
a `carbon-normal' population with [C/Fe]1D, LTE ≤ +1 dex.
Consideration of the A(C)1D, LTE versus [Fe/H]1D,
LTE diagram suggests that the current selection process is
strongly biased against stars with A(C)1D, LTE &#62; 7.3
(predominantly CEMP-s) while any bias against stars with A(C)1D,
LTE &#60; 7.3 and [C/Fe]1D,LTE &#62; +1
(predominantly CEMP-no) is not readily quantifiable given the
uncertainty in the SkyMapper v-band DR1.1 photometry. We find that the
metallicity distribution function of the observed sample has a power-law
slope of Δ(Log N)/Δ[Fe/H] = 1.5 ± 0.1 dex per dex for
-4.0 ≤ [Fe/H] ≤ -2.75, but appears to drop abruptly at [Fe/H] ≈
-4.2, in line with previous studies.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnras/stz2550</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1909.06227</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2011MNRAS.411L..51M</bibcode>
<title>Episodic disc accretion in the halo of the `old' pre-main-sequence cluster η Chamaeleontis</title>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Lawson, Warrick A.</author>
<author>Bessell, Michael S.</author>
<author>Bayliss, Daniel D. R.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia), AB(School of PEMS, University of New South Wales, Australian Defence Force Academy, Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia), AC(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia), AD(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society: Letters, Volume 411, Issue 1, pp. L51-L55.</journal>
<volume>411</volume>
<pubdate>Feb 2011</pubdate>
<page>L51</page>
<lastpage>L55</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>accretion</keyword>
<keyword>accretion discs</keyword>
<keyword>techniques: spectroscopic</keyword>
<keyword>stars: low-mass</keyword>
<keyword>stars: pre-main-sequence</keyword>
<keyword>open clusters and associations: individual: η Chamaeleontis</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>WILEY</origin>
<copyright>2010 The Authors Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society 2010 RAS</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011MNRAS.411L..51M&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011MNRAS.411L..51M&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011MNRAS.411L..51M&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011MNRAS.411L..51M&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011MNRAS.411L..51M&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>28</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011MNRAS.411L..51M&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>21</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011MNRAS.411L..51M&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2011MNRAS.411L..51M&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>13</count>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2011MNRAS.411L..51M</url>
<score>21.000</score>
<citations>21</citations>
<abstract>We present multi-epoch medium-resolution observations of two M4.5
candidate members in the halo of the ∼8 Myr η Chamaeleontis open
cluster. During six months of observations, both stars exhibited
variations in their Hα line profiles on time-scales of days to
months, with at least one episode of substantial activity attributable
to accretion from a circumstellar disc. We derive an accretion rate of
∼10-8.7 M⊙ yr-1 for this event,
with a rate of ∼10-10.6 M⊙ yr-1
in quiescence. Episodic accretion like that observed here suggests
existing surveys of accreting weak-lined T Tauri stars in young clusters
are likely incomplete and that gas dissipation time-scales calculated
from the fraction of accreting objects are underestimates. This paper
includes data gathered with the 6.5 meter Magellan Telescopes located at
Las Campanas Observatory, Chile.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1111/j.1745-3933.2010.00992.x</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1011.3816</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2016MNRAS.457.3191D</bibcode>
<title>A nearby young M dwarf with a wide, possibly planetary-mass companion</title>
<author>Deacon, N. R.</author>
<author>Schlieder, J. E.</author>
<author>Murphy, S. J.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Centre for Astrophysics Research, University of Hertfordshire, College Lane, Hatfield AL10 9AB, UK n.deacon2@herts.ac.uk), AB(NASA Ames Research Center, MS 245-6, Moffett Field, CA 94035, USA; Max Planck Institute for Astronomy, Konigstuhl 17, D-69117 Heidelberg, Germany), AC(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 457, Issue 3, p.3191-3199</journal>
<volume>457</volume>
<pubdate>Apr 2016</pubdate>
<page>3191</page>
<lastpage>3199</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>planets and satellites: detection</keyword>
<keyword>binaries: visual</keyword>
<keyword>brown dwarfs</keyword>
<keyword>stars: pre-main-sequence</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>OUP</origin>
<copyright>2016 The Authors Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Royal Astronomical Society</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016MNRAS.457.3191D&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016MNRAS.457.3191D&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016MNRAS.457.3191D&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016MNRAS.457.3191D&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016MNRAS.457.3191D&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>2</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016MNRAS.457.3191D&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>54</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016MNRAS.457.3191D&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>20</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016MNRAS.457.3191D&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016MNRAS.457.3191D&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>22</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2016MNRAS.457.3191D&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2016MNRAS.457.3191D</url>
<score>20.000</score>
<citations>20</citations>
<abstract>We present the identification of two previously known young objects in
the solar neighbourhood as a likely very wide binary. TYC 9486-927-1, an
active, rapidly rotating early-M dwarf, and 2MASS J21265040-8140293, a
low-gravity L3 dwarf previously identified as candidate members of the
∼45 Myr old Tucana-Horologium association (TucHor). An updated
proper motion measurement of the L3 secondary, and a detailed analysis
of the pair's kinematics in the context of known nearby, young stars,
reveals that they share common proper motion and are likely bound. New
observations and analyses reveal the primary exhibits Li 6708 Å
absorption consistent with M dwarfs younger than TucHor but older than
the ∼10 Myr TW Hydra association yielding an age range of 10-45 Myr.
A revised kinematic analysis suggests the space motions and positions of
the pair are closer to, but not entirely in agreement with, the ∼24
Myr old β Pictoris moving group. This revised 10-45 Myr age range
yields a mass range of 11.6-15 MJ for the secondary. It is
thus likely 2MASS J2126-8140 is the widest orbit planetary-mass object
known (&#62;4500 au) and its estimated mass, age, spectral type, and
Teff are similar to the well-studied planet β Pictoris
b. Because of their extreme separation and youth, this low-mass pair
provide an interesting case study for very wide binary formation and
evolution.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnras/stw172</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1601.06162</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2017MNRAS.468.1198B</bibcode>
<title>A stellar census of the nearby, young 32 Orionis group</title>
<author>Bell, Cameron P. M.</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Mamajek, Eric E.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Institute for Astronomy, ETH Zürich, Wolfgang-Pauli-Strasse 27, CH-8093 Zürich, Switzerland; Leibniz Institute for Astrophysics Potsdam (AIP), An der Sternwarte 16, D-14482 Potsdam, Germany), AB(School of Physical, Environmental and Mathematical Sciences, University of New South Wales, Northcott Drive, Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia), AC(Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Rochester, Rochester, NY 14627, USA; Jet Propulsion Laboratory, California Institute of Technology, 4800 Oak Grove Drive, Pasadena, CA 91109, USA)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 468, Issue 1, p.1198-1220</journal>
<volume>468</volume>
<pubdate>Jun 2017</pubdate>
<page>1198</page>
<lastpage>1220</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>stars: fundamental parameters</keyword>
<keyword>stars: kinematics and dynamics</keyword>
<keyword>stars: pre-main-sequence</keyword>
<keyword>open clusters and associations: general</keyword>
<keyword>solar neighbourhood</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>CROSSREF; OUP</origin>
<copyright>2017 The Authors Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Royal Astronomical Society</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2017MNRAS.468.1198B&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2017MNRAS.468.1198B&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2017MNRAS.468.1198B&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2017MNRAS.468.1198B&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2017MNRAS.468.1198B&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>1</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2017MNRAS.468.1198B&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>118</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2017MNRAS.468.1198B&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>18</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2017MNRAS.468.1198B&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2017MNRAS.468.1198B&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>84</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2017MNRAS.468.1198B&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2017MNRAS.468.1198B</url>
<score>18.000</score>
<citations>18</citations>
<abstract>The 32 Orionis group was discovered almost a decade ago and despite the
fact that it represents the first northern, young (age ∼ 25 Myr)
stellar aggregate within 100 pc of the Sun (d ≃ 93 pc), a
comprehensive survey for members and detailed characterization of the
group has yet to be performed. We present the first large-scale
spectroscopic survey for new (predominantly M type) members of the group
after combining kinematic and photometric data to select candidates with
Galactic space motion and positions in colour-magnitude space consistent
with membership. We identify 30 new members, increasing the number of
known 32 Ori group members by a factor of 3 and bringing the total
number of identified members to 46, spanning spectral types B5 to L1. We
also identify the lithium depletion boundary (LDB) of the group, I.e.
the luminosity at which lithium remains unburnt in a coeval population.
We estimate the age of the 32 Ori group independently using both
isochronal fitting and LDB analyses and find it is essentially coeval
with the β Pictoris moving group, with an age of 24 ± 4 Myr.
Finally, we have also searched for circumstellar disc hosts utilizing
the AllWISE catalogue. Although we find no evidence for warm, dusty
discs, we identify several stars with excess emission in the WISE W4
band at 22 μm. Based on the limited number of W4 detections, we
estimate a debris disc fraction of 32^{+12}_{-8} per cent for the 32 Ori
group.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnras/stx535</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1703.00015</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2015MNRAS.453.2220M</bibcode>
<title>New members of the TW Hydrae Association and two accreting M-dwarfs in Scorpius-Centaurus</title>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Lawson, Warrick A.</author>
<author>Bento, Joao</author>
<affiliation>AA(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; School of Physical, Environmental and Mathematical Sciences, University of New South Wales Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia simon.murphy@anu.edu.au), AB(School of Physical, Environmental and Mathematical Sciences, University of New South Wales Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia), AC(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 453, Issue 3, p.2220-2231</journal>
<volume>453</volume>
<pubdate>Nov 2015</pubdate>
<page>2220</page>
<lastpage>2231</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>stars: formation</keyword>
<keyword>stars: low-mass</keyword>
<keyword>stars: pre-main sequence</keyword>
<keyword>open clusters and associations: individual: TW Hydrae</keyword>
<keyword>Scorpius-Centaurus (Sco OB2)</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>OUP</origin>
<copyright>2015 The Authors Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Royal Astronomical Society</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.453.2220M&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.453.2220M&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.453.2220M&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.453.2220M&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.453.2220M&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>3</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.453.2220M&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>101</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.453.2220M&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>18</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.453.2220M&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.453.2220M&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>341</count>
</link>
<link type="ASSOCIATED">
  <name>Associated Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.453.2220M&#38;link_type=ASSOCIATED</url>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2015MNRAS.453.2220M&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2015MNRAS.453.2220M</url>
<score>18.000</score>
<citations>18</citations>
<abstract>We report the serendipitous discovery of several young mid-M stars found
during a search for new members of the 30-40 Myr-old Octans Association.
Only one of the stars may be considered a possible Octans(-Near) member.
However, two stars have proper motions, kinematic distances, radial
velocities, photometry and Li I λ6708 measurements consistent
with membership in the 8-10 Myr-old TW Hydrae Association. Another may
be an outlying member of TW Hydrae but has a velocity similar to that
predicted by membership in Octans. We also identify two new lithium-rich
members of the neighbouring Scorpius-Centaurus OB Association (Sco-Cen).
Both exhibit large 12 and 22 μm excesses and strong, variable
Hα emission which we attribute to accretion from circumstellar
discs. Such stars are thought to be incredibly rare at the ∼16 Myr
median age of Sco-Cen and they join only one other confirmed M-type and
three higher mass accretors outside of Upper Scorpius. The serendipitous
discovery of two accreting stars hosting large quantities of
circumstellar material may be indicative of a sizeable age spread in
Sco-Cen, or further evidence that disc dispersal and planet formation
time-scales are longer around lower mass stars. To aid future studies of
Sco-Cen, we also provide a newly compiled catalogue of 305 early-type
Hipparcos members with spectroscopic radial velocities sourced from the
literature.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnras/stv1745</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1507.08002</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2012ApJ...747L..23K</bibcode>
<title>2M1155-79 (= T Chamaeleontis B): A Low-mass, Wide-separation Companion to the nearby, &quot;Old&quot; T Tauri Star T Chamaeleontis</title>
<author>Kastner, Joel H.</author>
<author>Thompson, Emily A.</author>
<author>Montez, Rodolfo</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Bessell, Michael S.</author>
<author>Sacco, Giuseppe Germano</author>
<affiliation>AA(Center for Imaging Science and Laboratory for Multiwavelength Astrophysics, Rochester Institute of Technology, 54 Lomb Memorial Drive, Rochester, NY 14623, USA  jhk@cis.rit.edu), AB(Center for Imaging Science and Laboratory for Multiwavelength Astrophysics, Rochester Institute of Technology, 54 Lomb Memorial Drive, Rochester, NY 14623, USA ; West Irondequoit High School, Rochester, NY 14617, USA ), AC(Center for Imaging Science and Laboratory for Multiwavelength Astrophysics, Rochester Institute of Technology, 54 Lomb Memorial Drive, Rochester, NY 14623, USA ), AD(RSAA, Mount Stromlo Observatory, The Australian National University, ACT 2611, Australia ), AE(RSAA, Mount Stromlo Observatory, The Australian National University, ACT 2611, Australia ), AF(Center for Imaging Science and Laboratory for Multiwavelength Astrophysics, Rochester Institute of Technology, 54 Lomb Memorial Drive, Rochester, NY 14623, USA ; INAF-Osservatorio Astrofisico di Arcetri, Largo E. Fermi 5, Firenze 50125, Italy)</affiliation>
<journal>The Astrophysical Journal Letters, Volume 747, Issue 2, article id. L23, 6 pp. (2012).</journal>
<volume>747</volume>
<pubdate>Mar 2012</pubdate>
<page>L23</page>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>binaries: visual</keyword>
<keyword>circumstellar matter</keyword>
<keyword>protoplanetary disks</keyword>
<keyword>stars: pre-main sequence</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>IOP</origin>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012ApJ...747L..23K&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012ApJ...747L..23K&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012ApJ...747L..23K&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012ApJ...747L..23K&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012ApJ...747L..23K&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>1</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012ApJ...747L..23K&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>31</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012ApJ...747L..23K&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>17</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012ApJ...747L..23K&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012ApJ...747L..23K&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>23</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012ApJ...747L..23K&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2012ApJ...747L..23K</url>
<score>17.000</score>
<citations>17</citations>
<abstract>The early-K star T Cha, a member of the nearby (D ≈ 100 pc) epsilon
Cha Association, is a relatively &quot;old&quot; (age ~ 7 Myr) T Tauri star that
is still sporadically accreting from an orbiting disk whose inner
regions are now evidently being cleared by a close, substellar
companion. We report the identification, via analysis of proper motions,
serendipitous X-ray imaging spectroscopy, and follow-up optical
spectroscopy, of a new member of the epsilon Cha Association that is
very likely a low-mass companion to T Cha at a projected separation of
~38 kAU. The combined X-ray and optical spectroscopy data indicate that
the companion, T Cha B (= 2M1155-79), is a weak-lined T Tauri star
(wTTS) of spectral type M3 and age &#60;~ 10 Myr. The serendipitous X-ray
(XMM-Newton) observation of T Cha B, which targeted T Cha, also yields
serendipitous detections of two background wTTS in the Chamaeleon cloud
complex, including one newly discovered, low-mass member of the Cha
cloud pre-main-sequence (pre-MS) population. T Cha becomes the third
prominent example of a nearby, &quot;old&quot; yet still actively accreting,
K-type pre-MS star/disk system (the others being TW Hya and V4046 Sgr)
to feature a low-mass companion at very large (12-40 kAU) separation,
suggesting that such wide-separation companions may affect the
conditions and timescales for planet formation around solar-mass stars.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1088/2041-8205/747/2/L23</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1202.0262</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2019MNRAS.482.5553J</bibcode>
<title>Detection of a giant flare displaying quasi-periodic pulsations from a pre-main-sequence M star by the Next Generation Transit Survey</title>
<author>Jackman, James A. G.</author>
<author>Wheatley, Peter J.</author>
<author>Pugh, Chloe E.</author>
<author>Kolotkov, Dmitrii Y.</author>
<author>Broomhall, Anne-Marie</author>
<author>Kennedy, Grant M.</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Raddi, Roberto</author>
<author>Burleigh, Matthew R.</author>
<author>Casewell, Sarah L.</author>
<author>Eigmüller, Philipp</author>
<author>Gillen, Edward</author>
<author>Günther, Maximilian N.</author>
<author>Jenkins, James S.</author>
<author>Louden, Tom</author>
<author>McCormac, James</author>
<author>Raynard, Liam</author>
<author>Poppenhaeger, Katja</author>
<author>Udry, Stéphane</author>
<author>Watson, Christopher A.</author>
<author>West, Richard G.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Department of Physics, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL; Centre for Exoplanets and Habitability, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL), AB(Department of Physics, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL; Centre for Exoplanets and Habitability, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL 0000-0003-1452-2240), AC(Department of Physics, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL; Centre for Exoplanets and Habitability, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL), AD(Department of Physics, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL; Centre for Exoplanets and Habitability, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL), AE(Department of Physics, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL; Centre for Exoplanets and Habitability, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL; Institute of Advanced Studies, University of Warwick, Coventry CV4 7HS), AF(Department of Physics, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL; Centre for Exoplanets and Habitability, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL 0000-0001-6831-7547), AG(School of Physical, Environmental and Mathematical Sciences, University of New South Wales Canberra, ACT 2612, Australia 0000-0003-4932-7699), AH(Department of Physics, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL; Centre for Exoplanets and Habitability, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL; Dr. Remeis-Sternwarte, Friedrich Alexander Universität Erlangen-Nürnberg, Sternwartstr. 7, 96049 Bamberg, Germany), AI(Department of Physics and Astronomy, Leicester Institute of Space and Earth Observation, University of Leicester, University Road, Leicester LE1 7RH), AJ(Department of Physics and Astronomy, Leicester Institute of Space and Earth Observation, University of Leicester, University Road, Leicester LE1 7RH), AK(Institute of Planetary Research, German Aerospace Center, Rutherfordstrasse 2, 12489 Berlin, Germany; Center for Astronomy and Astrophysics, TU Berlin, Hardenbergstr. 36, D-10623 Berlin, Germany), AL(Astrophysics Group, Cavendish Laboratory, J.J. Thomson Avenue, Cambridge CB3 0HE), AM(Astrophysics Group, Cavendish Laboratory, J.J. Thomson Avenue, Cambridge CB3 0HE), AN(Departamento de Astronomia, Universidad de Chile, Casilla 36-D, Santiago, Chile), AO(Department of Physics, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL; Centre for Exoplanets and Habitability, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL 0000-0002-2574-356X), AP(Department of Physics, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL; Centre for Exoplanets and Habitability, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL), AQ(Department of Physics and Astronomy, Leicester Institute of Space and Earth Observation, University of Leicester, University Road, Leicester LE1 7RH), AR(Astrophysics Research Centre, Queen's University of Belfast, 1 University Road, Belfast BT7 1NN 0000-0003-1231-2194), AS(Department of Astronomy of the University of Geneva, Observatoire de Genéve, 51 ch des Maillettes, 1290 Versoix, Switzerland), AT(Astrophysics Research Centre, Queen's University of Belfast, 1 University Road, Belfast BT7 1NN), AU(Department of Physics, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL; Centre for Exoplanets and Habitability, University of Warwick, Gibbet Hill Road, Coventry CV4 7AL 0000-0001-6604-5533)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 482, Issue 4, p.5553-5566</journal>
<volume>482</volume>
<pubdate>Feb 2019</pubdate>
<page>5553</page>
<lastpage>5566</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>stars: flare</keyword>
<keyword>stars: individual: NGTS J121939.5-355557</keyword>
<keyword>stars: low-mass</keyword>
<keyword>stars: pre-main-sequence</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>OUP</origin>
<copyright>2018 The Author(s) Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Royal Astronomical Society</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.482.5553J&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.482.5553J&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.482.5553J&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.482.5553J&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.482.5553J&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>3</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.482.5553J&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>125</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.482.5553J&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>15</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.482.5553J&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.482.5553J&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>12</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.482.5553J&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<link type="OPENURL">
  <name>Library Link Server</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.482.5553J&#38;link_type=OPENURL</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2019MNRAS.482.5553J</url>
<score>15.000</score>
<citations>15</citations>
<abstract>We present the detection of an energetic flare on the pre-main-sequence
M3 star NGTS J121939.5-355557, which we estimate to be only 2 Myr old.
The flare had an energy of 3.2± ^{0.4}_{0.3}× 10^{36} erg
and a fractional amplitude of 7.2 ± 0.8, making it one of the
most energetic flares seen on an M star. The star is also X-ray active,
in the saturated regime with log LX/LBol = -3.1.
In the flare's peak, we have identified multimode quasi-periodic
pulsations formed of two statistically significant periods of
approximately 320 and 660 s. This flare is one of the largest amplitude
events to exhibit such pulsations. The shorter period mode is observed
to start after a short-lived spike in flux lasting around 30 s, which
would not have been resolved in Kepler or TESS short-cadence modes. Our
data show how the high cadence of the Next Generation Transient Survey
(NGTS) can be used to apply solar techniques to stellar flares and to
identify potential causes of the observed oscillations. We also discuss
the implications of this flare for the habitability of planets around M
star hosts and how NGTS can help our understanding of this.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnras/sty3036</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1811.02008</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2014MNRAS.438.3299K</bibcode>
<title>Evolution from protoplanetary to debris discs: the transition disc around HD 166191</title>
<author>Kennedy, G. M.</author>
<author>Murphy, S. J.</author>
<author>Lisse, C. M.</author>
<author>Ménard, F.</author>
<author>Sitko, M. L.</author>
<author>Wyatt, M. C.</author>
<author>Bayliss, D. D. R.</author>
<author>DeMeo, F. E.</author>
<author>Crawford, K. B.</author>
<author>Kim, D. L.</author>
<author>Rudy, R. J.</author>
<author>Russell, R. W.</author>
<author>Sibthorpe, B.</author>
<author>Skinner, M. A.</author>
<author>Zhou, G.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Institute of Astronomy, University of Cambridge, Madingley Road, Cambridge CB3 0HA, UK; gkennedy@ast.cam.ac.uk), AB(Astronomisches Rechen-Institut, Zentrum für Astronomie der Universität Heidelberg, D-69120 Heidelberg, Germany), AC(JHU-APL, 11100 Johns Hopkins Road, Laurel, MD 20723, USA), AD(UJF-Grenoble 1/CNRS-INSU, Institut de Planétologie et d'Astrophysique (IPAG) UMR 5274, F-38041 Grenoble, France; Laboratorio Franco-Chileno de Astronomia (UMI 3386: CNRS - U de Chile/PUC/U Conception), Santiago, Chile), AE(Department of Physics, University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, OH 45221-0011, USA), AF(Institute of Astronomy, University of Cambridge, Madingley Road, Cambridge CB3 0HA, UK), AG(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Mount Stromlo Observatory, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia), AH(Department of Earth, Atmospheric and Planetary Sciences, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 77 Massachusetts Avenue, Cambridge, MA 02139, USA), AI(The Aerospace Corporation, Mail Stop: M2-266, P.O. Box 92957, Los Angeles, CA 90009-2957, USA), AJ(The Aerospace Corporation, Mail Stop: M2-266, P.O. Box 92957, Los Angeles, CA 90009-2957, USA), AK(The Aerospace Corporation, Mail Stop: M2-266, P.O. Box 92957, Los Angeles, CA 90009-2957, USA), AL(The Aerospace Corporation, Mail Stop: M2-266, P.O. Box 92957, Los Angeles, CA 90009-2957, USA), AM(SRON Netherlands Institute for Space Research, NL-9747 AD Groningen, the Netherlands), AN(The Boeing Company, 535 Lipoa Pkwy, Kihei, HI 96753, USA), AO(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Mount Stromlo Observatory, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 438, Issue 4, p.3299-3309</journal>
<volume>438</volume>
<pubdate>Mar 2014</pubdate>
<page>3299</page>
<lastpage>3309</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>planets and satellites: formation</keyword>
<keyword>protoplanetary discs</keyword>
<keyword>circumstellar matter</keyword>
<keyword>stars: individual: HD 163296</keyword>
<keyword>stars: individual: HD 166191</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>OUP</origin>
<copyright>2014 The Authors Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Royal Astronomical Society</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2014MNRAS.438.3299K&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2014MNRAS.438.3299K&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2014MNRAS.438.3299K&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2014MNRAS.438.3299K&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2014MNRAS.438.3299K&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>1</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2014MNRAS.438.3299K&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>110</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2014MNRAS.438.3299K&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>13</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2014MNRAS.438.3299K&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2014MNRAS.438.3299K&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>30</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2014MNRAS.438.3299K&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2014MNRAS.438.3299K</url>
<score>13.000</score>
<citations>13</citations>
<abstract>HD 166191 has been identified by several studies as hosting a rare and
extremely bright warm debris disc with an additional outer cool disc
component. However, an alternative interpretation is that the star hosts
a disc that is currently in transition between a full gas disc and a
largely gas-free debris disc. With the help of new optical to
mid-infrared (IR) spectra and Herschel imaging, we argue that the latter
interpretation is supported in several ways: (i) we show that HD 166191
is comoving with the ∼4-Myr-old Herbig Ae star HD 163296, suggesting
that the two have the same age; (ii) the disc spectrum of HD 166191 is
well matched by a standard radiative transfer model of a gaseous
protoplanetary disc with an inner hole and (iii) the HD 166191 mid-IR
silicate feature is more consistent with similarly primordial objects.
We note some potential issues with the debris disc interpretation that
should be considered for such extreme objects, whose lifetime at the
current brightness is much shorter than the stellar age, or in the case
of the outer component requires a mass comparable to the solid component
of the solar nebula. These aspects individually and collectively argue
that HD 166191 is a 4-5 Myr old star that hosts a gaseous transition
disc. Though it does not argue in favour of either scenario, we find
strong evidence for 3-5 μm disc variability. We place HD 166191 in
context with discs at different evolutionary stages, showing that it is
a potentially important object for understanding the protoplanetary to
debris disc transition.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnras/stt2435</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1312.4531</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2019ApJ...872...92F</bibcode>
<title>The Planet Formation Potential around a 45 Myr Old Accreting M Dwarf</title>
<author>Flaherty, Kevin</author>
<author>Hughes, A. Meredith</author>
<author>Mamajek, Eric E.</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Department of Astronomy and Department of Physics, Williams College, Williamstown, MA 01267, USA ;  Van Vleck Observatory, Astronomy Department, Wesleyan University, 96 Foss Hill Drive, Middletown, CT 06459, USA; kmf4@williams.edu 0000-0003-2657-1314), AB(Van Vleck Observatory, Astronomy Department, Wesleyan University, 96 Foss Hill Drive, Middletown, CT 06459, USA), AC(Jet Propulsion Laboratory, California Institute of Technology, 4800 Oak Grove Drive, Pasadena, CA 91109, USA ;  Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Rochester, 500 Wilson Boulevard, Rochester, NY 14627, USA 0000-0003-2008-1488), AD(School of Physical, Environment and Mathematical Sciences, University of New South Wales Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 872, Issue 1, article id. 92, 6 pp. (2019).</journal>
<volume>872</volume>
<pubdate>Feb 2019</pubdate>
<page>92</page>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>circumstellar matter</keyword>
<keyword>stars: individual: WISE J080822.18-644357.3</keyword>
<keyword>submillimeter: planetary systems</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>IOP</origin>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019ApJ...872...92F&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019ApJ...872...92F&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019ApJ...872...92F&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019ApJ...872...92F&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019ApJ...872...92F&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>2</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019ApJ...872...92F&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>105</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019ApJ...872...92F&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>9</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019ApJ...872...92F&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019ApJ...872...92F&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>11</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019ApJ...872...92F&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2019ApJ...872...92F</url>
<score>9.000</score>
<citations>9</citations>
<abstract>Debris disk detections around M dwarfs are rare, and so far no gas
emission has been detected from an M dwarf debris disk. This makes the
45 Myr old M dwarf WISE J080822.18-644357.3 a bit of a curiosity; it has
a strong infrared excess at an age beyond the lifetime of a typical
planet-forming disk, and also exhibits broad Hα emission
consistent with active accretion from a gaseous disk. To better
understand the cold gas and dust properties of this system, we obtained
ALMA observations of the 1.3 mm continuum and the
CO/13CO/C18O J = 2-1 emission lines. No cold
CO gas is detected from this system, ruling out a gas-rich
protoplanetary disk. Unresolved dust continuum emission is detected at a
flux of 198 ± 15 μJy, consistent with 0.057 ± 0.006 M
⊕ worth of optically thin dust, and consistent with
being generated through a collisional cascade induced by large bodies at
radii &#60;16 au. With a sufficiently strong stellar wind, dust grains
released in the outer disk can migrate inward via PR drag, potentially
serving as a source of grains for the strong infrared excess.</abstract>
<DOI>10.3847/1538-4357/aaf794</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1812.04124</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2019MNRAS.485.5153M</bibcode>
<title>Keck HIRES spectroscopy of SkyMapper commissioning survey candidate extremely metal-poor stars</title>
<author>Marino, A. F.</author>
<author>Da Costa, G. S.</author>
<author>Casey, A. R.</author>
<author>Asplund, M.</author>
<author>Bessell, M. S.</author>
<author>Frebel, A.</author>
<author>Keller, S. C.</author>
<author>Lind, K.</author>
<author>Mackey, A. D.</author>
<author>Murphy, S. J.</author>
<author>Nordlander, T.</author>
<author>Norris, J. E.</author>
<author>Schmidt, B. P.</author>
<author>Yong, D.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, Australian National University, ACT 2611, Australia; Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia `Galileo Galilei' - Univ. di Padova, Vicolo dell'Osservatorio 3, Padova, IT-35122, Italy; Centro di Ateneo di Studi e Attività Spaziali `Giuseppe Colombo' - CISAS, Via Venezia 15, Padova, IT-35131, Italy 0000-0002-1276-5487), AB(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, Australian National University, ACT 2611, Australia 0000-0001-7019-649X), AC(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, Australian National University, ACT 2611, Australia; School of Physics and Astronomy, Monash University, Wellington Rd, Clayton, VIC 3800, Australia; Faculty of Information Technology, Monash University, Wellington Rd, Clayton, VIC 3800, Australia 0000-0003-0174-0564), AD(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, Australian National University, ACT 2611, Australia; Center of Excellence for Astrophysics in Three Dimensions (ASTRO-3D), Australia 0000-0002-5804-3682), AE(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, Australian National University, ACT 2611, Australia 0000-0001-7801-1410), AF(Department of Physics and Kavli Institute for Astrophysics and Space Research, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA 02139, USA 0000-0002-2139-7145), AG(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, Australian National University, ACT 2611, Australia), AH(Max-Planck-Institut für Astronomie, Königstuhl 17, D-69117 Heidelberg, Germany; Observational Astrophysics, Department of Physics and Astronomy, Uppsala University, Box 516, SE-751 20 Uppsala, Sweden), AI(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, Australian National University, ACT 2611, Australia), AJ(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, Australian National University, ACT 2611, Australia; School of Physical, Environmental and Mathematical Sciences, University of New South Wales, Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia 0000-0003-4932-7699), AK(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, Australian National University, ACT 2611, Australia; Center of Excellence for Astrophysics in Three Dimensions (ASTRO-3D), Australia), AL(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, Australian National University, ACT 2611, Australia), AM(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, Australian National University, ACT 2611, Australia 0000-0001-6589-1287), AN(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, Australian National University, ACT 2611, Australia 0000-0002-6502-1406)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 485, Issue 4, p.5153-5167</journal>
<volume>485</volume>
<pubdate>Jun 2019</pubdate>
<page>5153</page>
<lastpage>5167</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>stars: abundances</keyword>
<keyword>stars: Population II</keyword>
<keyword>Galaxy: halo</keyword>
<keyword>Galaxy: stellar content</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>OUP</origin>
<copyright>2019 The Author(s) Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Royal Astronomical Society</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.485.5153M&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.485.5153M&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.485.5153M&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.485.5153M&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.485.5153M&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>52</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.485.5153M&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>7</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.485.5153M&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.485.5153M&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>19</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.485.5153M&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<link type="OPENURL">
  <name>Library Link Server</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2019MNRAS.485.5153M&#38;link_type=OPENURL</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2019MNRAS.485.5153M</url>
<score>7.000</score>
<citations>7</citations>
<abstract>We present results from the analysis of high-resolution spectra obtained
with the Keck HIRES spectrograph for a sample of 17 candidate extremely
metal-poor (EMP) stars originally selected from commissioning data
obtained with the SkyMapper telescope. Fourteen of the stars have not
been observed previously at high dispersion. Three have [Fe/H] ≤
-3.0, while the remainder, with two more metal-rich exceptions, have
-3.0 ≤ [Fe/H] ≤ -2.0 dex. Apart from Fe, we also derive abundances
for the elements C, N, Na, Mg, Al, Si, Ca, Sc, Ti, Cr, Mn, Co, Ni, and
Zn, and for n-capture elements Sr, Ba, and Eu. None of the current
sample of stars is found to be carbon-rich. In general, our chemical
abundances follow previous trends found in the literature, although we
note that two of the most metal-poor stars show very low [Ba/Fe]
(∼-1.7) coupled with low [Sr/Ba] (∼-0.3). Such stars are
relatively rare in the Galactic halo. One further star, and possibly two
others, meet the criteria for classification as a r-I star. This study,
together with that of Jacobson et al. (2015), completes the outcomes of
the SkyMapper commissioning data survey for EMP stars.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnras/stz645</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1902.10611</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2020MNRAS.494...62L</bibcode>
<title>2MASS J15460752-6258042: a mid-M dwarf hosting a prolonged accretion disc</title>
<author>Lee, Jinhee</author>
<author>Song, Inseok</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon</author>
<affiliation>AA(School of Space Research, Kyung Hee University, 1732, Deogyeong-Daero, Giheung-gu, Yongin-shi, Gyuonggi-do 17104, South Korea; Department of Physics and Astronomy, The University of Georgia, Athens, GA 30602, USA), AB(Department of Physics and Astronomy, The University of Georgia, Athens, GA 30602, USA), AC(School of Science, University of New South Wales Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 494, Issue 1, pp.62-68</journal>
<volume>494</volume>
<pubdate>May 2020</pubdate>
<page>62</page>
<lastpage>68</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>accretion</keyword>
<keyword>accretion discs</keyword>
<keyword>stars: late-type</keyword>
<keyword>stars: pre-main-sequence</keyword>
<keyword>open clusters and associations: individual</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>OUP</origin>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.494...62L&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.494...62L&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.494...62L&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.494...62L&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.494...62L&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>78</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.494...62L&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>6</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.494...62L&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.494...62L&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>29</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.494...62L&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<link type="OPENURL">
  <name>Library Link Server</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.494...62L&#38;link_type=OPENURL</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2020MNRAS.494...62L</url>
<score>6.000</score>
<citations>6</citations>
<abstract>We report the discovery of the oldest (∼55 Myr) mid-M type star
known to host ongoing accretion. 2MASS J15460752-6258042 (2M1546,
spectral type M5, 59.2 pc) shows spectroscopic signs of accretion such
as strong H α, He I, and [O I] emission lines, from which we
estimate an accretion rate of ∼10-10 M⊙
yr-1. Considering the clearly detected infrared excess in all
WISE bands, the shape of its spectral energy distribution (SED) and its
age, we believe that the star is surrounded by a transitional disc,
clearly with some gas still present at inner radii. The position and
kinematics of the star from Gaia DR2 and our own radial-velocity
measurements suggest membership in the nearby ∼55 Myr-old Argus
moving group. At only 59 pc from Earth, 2M1546 is one of the nearest
accreting mid-M dwarfs, making it an ideal target for studying the upper
limit on the lifetimes of gas-rich discs around low-mass stars.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnras/staa689</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:2002.12600</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2020MNRAS.495L.129K</bibcode>
<title>The closest extremely low-mass white dwarf to the Sun</title>
<author>Kawka, Adela</author>
<author>Simpson, Jeffrey D.</author>
<author>Vennes, Stéphane</author>
<author>Bessell, Michael S.</author>
<author>Da Costa, Gary S.</author>
<author>Marino, Anna F.</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<affiliation>AA(International Centre for Radio Astronomy Research, Curtin University, GPO Box U1987, Perth, WA 6845, Australia 0000-0002-4485-6471 adela.kawka@curtin.edu.au), AB(School of Physics, UNSW Sydney, Sydney, NSW 2052, Australia 0000-0002-8165-2507), AC(Mathematical Sciences Institute, The Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 0200, Australia), AD(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AE(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia 0000-0001-7019-649X), AF(Dipartmento di Fisica e Astronomica Galileo Galilei, Università di Padova, Vicolo dell'Osservatorio 3, I-35122 Padova, Italy; Centro di Ateneo di Studi e Attivita Spaziali 'Giuseppe Colombo', CISAS, Via Venezia 15, I-35131 Padova, Italy 0000-0002-1276-5487), AG(School of Science, The University of New South Wales, Canberra, Canberra ACT 2600, Australia 0000-0003-4932-7699)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society: Letters, Volume 495, Issue 1, pp.L129-L134</journal>
<volume>495</volume>
<pubdate>Jun 2020</pubdate>
<page>L129</page>
<lastpage>L134</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>binaries: close</keyword>
<keyword>stars: individual: 2MASS J050051.85-093054.9</keyword>
<keyword>white dwarfs</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>OUP</origin>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.495L.129K&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.495L.129K&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.495L.129K&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.495L.129K&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.495L.129K&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>1</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.495L.129K&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>50</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.495L.129K&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>5</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.495L.129K&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.495L.129K&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>3</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.495L.129K&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<link type="OPENURL">
  <name>Library Link Server</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.495L.129K&#38;link_type=OPENURL</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2020MNRAS.495L.129K</url>
<score>5.000</score>
<citations>5</citations>
<abstract>We present the orbit and properties of 2MASS J050051.85-093054.9,
establishing it as the closest (d ≍ 71 pc) extremely low-mass
white dwarf to the Sun. We find that this star is hydrogen rich with
$T_\textrm {eff}\approx 10\, 500$ K, log g ≍ 5.9, and, following
evolutionary models, has a mass of ≍0.17 M⊙.
Independent analysis of radial velocity and Transiting Exoplanet Survey
Satellite(TESS) photometric time series reveals an orbital period of
≍9.5 h. Its high velocity amplitude ( $K\approx 144~\textrm {km}\,
\textrm {s}^{-1}$ ) produces a measurable Doppler beaming effect in the
TESSlight curve with an amplitude of 1 mmag. The unseen companion is
most likely a faint white dwarf. J0500-0930 belongs to a class of
post-common envelope systems that will most likely merge through
unstable mass transfer and in specific circumstances lead to Type Ia
supernova explosions.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnrasl/slaa068</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:2004.07556</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2020MNRAS.491.4902M</bibcode>
<title>THOR 42: A touchstone ∼24 Myr-old eclipsing binary spanning the fully convective boundary</title>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Lawson, Warrick A.</author>
<author>Onken, Christopher A.</author>
<author>Yong, David</author>
<author>Da Costa, Gary S.</author>
<author>Zhou, George</author>
<author>Mamajek, Eric E.</author>
<author>Bell, Cameron P. M.</author>
<author>Bessell, Michael S.</author>
<author>Feinstein, Adina D.</author>
<affiliation>AA(School of Science, The University of New South Wales, Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia; Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia 0000-0003-4932-7699), AB(School of Science, The University of New South Wales, Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia), AC(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; Australian Research Council Centre of Excellence for All-Sky Astrophysics (CAASTRO)), AD(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; Australian Research Council Centre of Excellence for All-Sky Astrophysics in 3D (ASTRO 3D)), AE(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia 0000-0001-7019-649X), AF(Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics, 60 Garden Street, Cambridge, MA 02138, USA), AG(Jet Propulsion Laboratory, California Institute of Technology, 4800 Oak Grove Dr., Pasadena, CA 91109, USA; Department of Physics &#38; Astronomy, University of Rochester, 500 Wilson Blvd., Rochester, NY 14627, USA), AH(Leibniz Institute for Astrophysics Potsdam (AIP), An der Sternwarte 16, D-14482 Potsdam, Germany 0000-0003-0642-6558), AI(Research School of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia; Australian Research Council Centre of Excellence for All-Sky Astrophysics in 3D (ASTRO 3D)), AJ(Department of Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, University of Chicago, 5640 S. Ellis Ave, Chicago, IL 60637, USA)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 491, Issue 4, p.4902-4924</journal>
<volume>491</volume>
<pubdate>Feb 2020</pubdate>
<page>4902</page>
<lastpage>4924</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>binaries: eclipsing</keyword>
<keyword>binaries: spectroscopic</keyword>
<keyword>stars: evolution</keyword>
<keyword>stars: fundamental parameters</keyword>
<keyword>stars: low mass</keyword>
<keyword>stars: pre-main-sequence</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>OUP</origin>
<copyright>2019 The Author(s) Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Royal Astronomical Society</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491.4902M&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491.4902M&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491.4902M&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491.4902M&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491.4902M&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>1</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491.4902M&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>122</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491.4902M&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>4</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491.4902M&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491.4902M&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>33</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491.4902M&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<link type="OPENURL">
  <name>Library Link Server</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491.4902M&#38;link_type=OPENURL</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2020MNRAS.491.4902M</url>
<score>4.000</score>
<citations>4</citations>
<abstract>We present the characterization of CRTS J055255.7-004426 (=THOR 42), a
young eclipsing binary comprising two pre-main sequence M dwarfs
(combined spectral type M3.5). This nearby (103 pc), short-period (0.859
d) system was recently proposed as a member of the ∼24 Myr-old 32
Orionis Moving Group. Using ground- and space-based photometry in
combination with medium- and high-resolution spectroscopy, we model the
light and radial velocity curves to derive precise system parameters.
The resulting component masses and radii are 0.497 ± 0.005 and
0.205 ± 0.002 {M}_{⊙ }, and 0.659 ± 0.003 and 0.424
± 0.002 {R}_{⊙ }, respectively. With mass and radius
uncertainties of ∼1 per cent and ∼0.5 per cent, respectively,
THOR 42 is one of the most precisely characterized pre-main sequence
eclipsing binaries known. Its systemic velocity, parallax, proper
motion, colour-magnitude diagram placement, and enlarged radii are all
consistent with membership in the 32 Ori Group. The system provides a
unique opportunity to test pre-main sequence evolutionary models at an
age and mass range not well constrained by observation. From the radius
and mass measurements we derive ages of 22-26 Myr using standard
(non-magnetic) models, in excellent agreement with the age of the group.
However, none of the models can simultaneously reproduce the observed
mass, radius, temperature, and luminosity of the coeval components. In
particular, their H-R diagram ages are 2-4 times younger and we infer
masses ∼50 per cent smaller than the dynamical values.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnras/stz3198</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1911.05925</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2020MNRAS.491..215B</bibcode>
<title>A kinematically unbiased, all-sky search for nearby, young, low-mass stars</title>
<author>Binks, Alexander S.</author>
<author>Chalifour, Matthieu</author>
<author>Kastner, Joel H.</author>
<author>Rodriguez, David</author>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Principe, David A.</author>
<author>Punzi, Kristina</author>
<author>Sacco, Germano G.</author>
<author>Hernández, Jesús</author>
<affiliation>AA(Astrophysics Group, Keele University, Keele, ST5 5BG, UK; Instituto de Radioastronomía y Astrofísica, Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM), Antigua Carretera a Pátzcuaro #8701 Ex-Hda. San José de la Huerta, Morelia, Michoacán, México. C.P. 58089 0000-0001-5976-4644), AB(Center for Imaging Science, 54 Lomb Memorial Drive, Rochester NY 14623, USA; Physics &#38; Astronomy Department, Swarthmore College, 500 College Avenue, Swarthmore, PA 19081-1397, USA), AC(Center for Imaging Science, 54 Lomb Memorial Drive, Rochester NY 14623, USA), AD(Space Telesccope Science Institute, 3700 San Martin Drive, Baltimore, MD 21218, USA), AE(School of Science, The University of New South Wales, Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia 0000-0003-4932-7699), AF(MIT Kavli Institute for Astrophysics and Space Research, 70 Vassar St, Cambridge, MA 02109, USA), AG(Astronomy Department, Wellesley College, 106 Central Street, Wellesley, MA 02481, USA), AH(Arcetri Observatory, 5, Largo Enrico Fermi, I-50125 Florence, Italy), AI(Instituto de Astronomía, UNAM, Unidad Académica en Ensenada, Ensenada 22860, México)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 491, Issue 1, p.215-234</journal>
<volume>491</volume>
<pubdate>Jan 2020</pubdate>
<page>215</page>
<lastpage>234</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>stars: kinematics and dynamics</keyword>
<keyword>stars: late-type</keyword>
<keyword>stars: pre-main-sequence</keyword>
<keyword>solar neighbourhood</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>OUP</origin>
<copyright>2019 The Author(s) Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Royal Astronomical Society</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491..215B&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491..215B&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491..215B&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491..215B&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491..215B&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>2</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491..215B&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>118</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491..215B&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>4</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491..215B&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491..215B&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>52</count>
</link>
<link type="ASSOCIATED">
  <name>Associated Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491..215B&#38;link_type=ASSOCIATED</url>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491..215B&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<link type="OPENURL">
  <name>Library Link Server</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020MNRAS.491..215B&#38;link_type=OPENURL</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2020MNRAS.491..215B</url>
<score>4.000</score>
<citations>4</citations>
<abstract>The past two decades have seen dramatic progress in our knowledge of the
population of young stars of age &#60; 200 Myr that lie within 150 pc of
the Sun. These nearby, young stars, most of which are found in loose,
comoving groups, provide the opportunity to explore (among many other
things) the dissolution of stellar clusters and their diffusion into the
field star population. Here, we exploit the combination of astrometric
and photometric data from Gaia and photometric data from GALEX (UV) and
2MASS (near-IR) in an attempt to identify additional nearby, young,
late-type stars. Specifically, we present a sample of 146 GALEX
UV-selected late-type (predominantly K-type) field stars with Gaia-based
distances &#60; 125 pc (based on Gaia Data Release 1) that have
isochronal ages &#60; 80 Myr even if equal-components binaries. We
investigate the spectroscopic and kinematic properties of this sample.
Despite their young isochronal ages, only ∼10 per cent of stars
among this sample can be confidently associated with established nearby,
young moving groups (MGs). These candidate MG members include five stars
newly identified in this study. The vast majority of our sample of 146
nearby young star candidates have anomalous kinematics relative to the
known MGs. These stars may hence represent a previously unrecognized
population of young stars that has recently mixed into the older field
star population. We discuss the implications and caveats of such a
hypothesis - including the intriguing fact that, in addition to their
non-young-star-like kinematics, the majority of the UV-selected,
isochronally young field stars within 50 pc appear surprisingly X-ray
faint.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnras/stz3019</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1910.10463</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2020A&amp;A...634A.128N</bibcode>
<title>Sporadic and intense accretion in a 1 Myr-old brown dwarf candidate</title>
<author>Nguyen-Thanh, D.</author>
<author>Phan-Bao, N.</author>
<author>Murphy, S. J.</author>
<author>Bessell, M. S.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Department of Physics, International University, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam pbngoc@hcmiu.edu.vn; Vietnam National University, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam; Faculty of Physics and Engineering Physics, University of Science, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam), AB(Department of Physics, International University, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam; Vietnam National University, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam), AC(School of Science, University of New South Wales Canberra, ACT, 2600, Australia; Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Cotter Rd, Weston, ACT 2611, Australia), AD(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Cotter Rd, Weston, ACT 2611, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>Astronomy &#38; Astrophysics, Volume 634, id.A128, 15 pp.</journal>
<volume>634</volume>
<pubdate>Feb 2020</pubdate>
<page>A128</page>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>techniques: spectroscopic</keyword>
<keyword>techniques: photometric</keyword>
<keyword>brown dwarfs</keyword>
<keyword>circumstellar matter</keyword>
<keyword>stars: low-mass</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>EDP Sciences</origin>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020A%26A...634A.128N&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020A%26A...634A.128N&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020A%26A...634A.128N&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020A%26A...634A.128N&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020A%26A...634A.128N&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>56</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020A%26A...634A.128N&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>3</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020A%26A...634A.128N&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020A%26A...634A.128N&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>90</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2020A%26A...634A.128N&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2020A%26A...634A.128N</url>
<score>3.000</score>
<citations>3</citations>
<abstract>Context. Studying the accretion process in very low-mass objects has
important implications for understanding their formation mechanism. Many
nearby late-M dwarfs that have previously been identified in the field
are in fact young brown dwarf members of nearby young associations. Some
of them are still accreting. They are therefore excellent targets for
further studies of the accretion process in the very low-mass regime at
different stages.  Aims: We aim to search for accreting young
brown dwarf candidates in a sample of 85 nearby late-M dwarfs. 
Methods: Using photometric data from DENIS, 2MASS, and WISE, we
constructed the spectral energy distribution of the late- M dwarfs based
on BT-Settl models to detect infrared excesses. We then searched for
lithium and Hα emission in candidates that exhibit infrared
excesses to confirm their youth and the presence of accretion. 
Results: Among the 85 late-M dwarfs, only DENIS-P J1538317-103850 (M5.5)
shows strong infrared excesses in WISE bands. The detection of lithium
absorption in the M5.5 dwarf and its Gaia trigonometric parallax
indicate an age of ~1 Myr and a mass of 47 MJ. The Hα
emission line in the brown dwarf shows significant variability that
indicates sporadic accretion. This 1 Myr-old brown dwarf also exhibits
intense accretion bursts with accretion rates of up to 10-7.9
M⊙ yr-1.  Conclusions: Our detection of
sporadic accretion in one of the youngest brown dwarfs might imply that
sporadic accretion at early stages could play an important role in the
formation of brown dwarfs. Very low-mass cores would not be able to
accrete enough material to become stars, and thus they end up as brown
dwarfs.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1051/0004-6361/201936810</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:2001.08890</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2012MNRAS.424..625M</bibcode>
<title>RX J0942.7-7726AB: an isolated pre-main-sequence wide binary</title>
<author>Murphy, Simon J.</author>
<author>Lawson, Warrick A.</author>
<author>Bessell, Michael S.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia), AB(School of PEMS, University of New South Wales, Australian Defence Force Academy, Canberra, ACT 2600, Australia), AC(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, The Australian National University, Cotter Road, Weston Creek, ACT 2611, Australia)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 424, Issue 1, pp. 625-634.</journal>
<volume>424</volume>
<pubdate>Jul 2012</pubdate>
<page>625</page>
<lastpage>634</lastpage>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>binaries: visual</keyword>
<keyword>stars: formation</keyword>
<keyword>stars: kinematics and dynamics</keyword>
<keyword>stars: low-mass</keyword>
<keyword>stars: pre-main-sequence</keyword>
<keyword>open clusters and associations</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>WILEY</origin>
<copyright>© 2012 The Authors Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society © 2012 RAS</copyright>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012MNRAS.424..625M&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="EJOURNAL" access="open">
  <name>Electronic On-line Article (HTML)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012MNRAS.424..625M&#38;link_type=EJOURNAL</url>
</link>
<link type="ARTICLE" access="open">
  <name>Full Printable Article (PDF/Postscript)</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012MNRAS.424..625M&#38;link_type=ARTICLE</url>
</link>
<link type="PREPRINT" access="open">
  <name>arXiv e-print</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012MNRAS.424..625M&#38;link_type=PREPRINT</url>
</link>
<link type="DATA">
  <name>On-line Data</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012MNRAS.424..625M&#38;link_type=DATA</url>
  <count>1</count>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012MNRAS.424..625M&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>90</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012MNRAS.424..625M&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>3</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012MNRAS.424..625M&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="SIMBAD">
  <name>SIMBAD Objects</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012MNRAS.424..625M&#38;link_type=SIMBAD</url>
  <count>38</count>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012MNRAS.424..625M&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2012MNRAS.424..625M</url>
<score>3.000</score>
<citations>3</citations>
<abstract>We report the discovery of two young M-dwarfs, RX J0942.7-7726 (M1) and
2MASS J09424157-7727130 (M4.5), that were found only 42 arcsec apart in
a survey for pre-main-sequence stars surrounding the open cluster η
Chamaeleontis. Both stars have congruent proper motions and
near-infrared photometry. Medium-resolution spectroscopy reveals that
they are coeval (age 8-12 Myr), codistant (100-150 pc) and thus almost
certainly form a true wide binary with a projected separation of
4000-6000 au. The system appears too old and dynamically fragile to have
originated in η Cha and a trace-back analysis argues for its birth
in or near the Scorpius-Centaurus OB association (Sco-Cen). RX
J0942.7-7726AB joins a growing group of wide binaries kinematically
linked to Sco-Cen, suggesting that such fragile systems can survive the
turbulent environment of their natal molecular clouds while still being
dispersed with large velocities. Conversely, the small radial velocity
difference between the stars (2.7 ± 1.0 km s-1) could
mean the system is unbound, a result of the coincidental ejection of two
single stars with similar velocity vectors from the OB association early
in its evolution.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.21243.x</DOI>
<eprintid>arXiv:1205.1510</eprintid>
</record>

<record refereed="true" type="PHDTHESIS">
<bibcode>2012PhDT.........3M</bibcode>
<title>Revealing the Chamaeleon: Young, low-mass stars surrounding eta and epsilon Chamaeleontis</title>
<author>Murphy, S. J.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Mount Stromlo Observatory, Australian National University, Canberra, Australia murphysj@mso.anu.edu.au)</affiliation>
<journal>Thesis (PhD). AUSTRALIAN NATIONAL UNIVERSITY</journal>
<pubdate>Jan 2012</pubdate>
<keywords>
<keyword>eta Chamaeleontis</keyword>
<keyword>epsilon Chamaeleontis</keyword>
<keyword>dynamical evolution</keyword>
<keyword>accretion</keyword>
<keyword>circumstellar disks</keyword>
<keyword>wide binaries</keyword>
<keyword>open clusters</keyword>
<keyword>associations</keyword>
<keyword>low-mass stars</keyword>
<keyword>star formation</keyword>
<keyword>moving groups</keyword>
<keyword>pre-main sequence stars </keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>AUTHOR</origin>
<link type="ABSTRACT">
  <name>Abstract</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012PhDT.........3M&#38;link_type=ABSTRACT</url>
</link>
<link type="REFERENCES">
  <name>References in the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012PhDT.........3M&#38;link_type=REFERENCES</url>
  <count>45</count>
</link>
<link type="CITATIONS">
  <name>Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012PhDT.........3M&#38;link_type=CITATIONS</url>
  <count>3</count>
</link>
<link type="REFCIT">
  <name>Refereed Citations to the Article</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012PhDT.........3M&#38;link_type=REFCIT</url>
</link>
<link type="AR">
  <name>Also-Read Articles</name>
  <url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/nph-data_query?bibcode=2012PhDT.........3M&#38;link_type=AR</url>
</link>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2012PhDT.........3M</url>
<score>3.000</score>
<citations>3</citations>
<abstract>The deep southern sky surrounding the Chamaeleon dark clouds is abundant
with pre-main sequence stars of various ages. Because of their youth
(5-10 Myr) and proximity (d~100 pc), members of the open cluster eta 
Chamaeleontis and the nearby epsilon Chamaeleontis Association are ideal
laboratories to study the formation and evolution of extrasolar
planetary systems. To better understand their role as potential planet
hosts, this thesis explores the formation, dynamical evolution,
accretion and disk properties of both groups' low-mass members.

The notable lack of low-mass stars in the young open cluster eta Cha has
long been puzzling. Two possible explanations have been suggested; a
top-heavy initial mass function or dynamical evolution, which
preferentially ejected the low-mass members. Previous efforts to find
these stars several degrees from the cluster core have been
unsuccessful. By undertaking a wider (95 sq deg) photometric and proper
motion survey with extensive follow-up spectroscopy, we have identified
eight low-mass stars that were ejected from eta Cha over the past 5-10
Myr. Comparison with recent simulations shows our results are consistent
with a dynamical origin for the current configuration of the cluster,
without the need to invoke an initial mass function deficient in
low-mass objects.

Two of the dispersed members exhibited strong, variable H-alpha emission
during our observations, including a star which had an event suggestive
of accretion from a circumstellar disk. New infrared photometry confirms
the presence of the disk. This star demonstrates that infrequent,
episodic accretion can continue at low levels long after most disks
around `old' pre-main sequence stars have dissipated.

Another two confirmed non-members are slightly older than the cluster,
but are only 42 arcseconds apart and share similar kinematics and
distances. We show that they almost certainly form a wide (4000-6000 AU)
~10 Myr-old binary at 100-150 pc. The system is one of the widest
pre-main sequence binaries known. Its isolation and dynamical fragility
put strong constraints on any birthplace and mode of formation, which we
propose was in a turbulent gas filament in the vicinity of the
Scorpius-Centaurus OB Association.

In addition to eta Cha, we have also examined membership of the unbound
epsilon Cha Association, which lies some 10 degrees to the east and has
a similar age, distance and kinematics. The two groups were almost
certainly born in the outer regions of Sco-Cen only a few million years
apart. Many members of epsilon Cha have been proposed in the decade
since its discovery. After considering the kinematics of candidates from
the literature, we have confirmed 11 further stars as likely members.
Many new members possess infrared spectral energy distributions
attributable to circumstellar disks, including four stars with strong
H-alpha and forbidden emission which are actively accreting material.</abstract>
</record>

<record article="true" type="ARTICLE">
<bibcode>2020MNRAS.tmp.3219C</bibcode>
<title>Exploring the Galaxy's halo and very metal-weak thick disk with SkyMapper and Gaia DR2</title>
<author>Cordoni, G.</author>
<author>Da Costa, G. S.</author>
<author>Yong, D.</author>
<author>Mackey, A. D.</author>
<author>Marino, A. F.</author>
<author>Monty, S.</author>
<author>Nordlander, T.</author>
<author>Norris, J. E.</author>
<author>Asplund, M.</author>
<author>Bessell, M. S.</author>
<author>Casey, A. R.</author>
<author>Frebel, A.</author>
<author>Lind, K.</author>
<author>Murphy, S. J.</author>
<author>Schmidt, B. P.</author>
<author>Gao, X. D.</author>
<author>Xylakis-Dornbusch, T.</author>
<author>Amarsi, A. M.</author>
<author>Milone, A. P.</author>
<affiliation>AA(Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia &quot;Galileo Galilei&quot; - Università di Padova, Vicolo dell'Osservatorio 3, Padova, IT-35122 0000-0002-7690-7683 giacomo.cordoni@phd.unipd.it), AB(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AC(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AD(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AE(Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia &quot;Galileo Galilei&quot; - Università di Padova, Vicolo dell'Osservatorio 3, Padova, IT-35122 0000-0002-1276-5487), AF(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia 0000-0002-9225-5822), AG(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia 0000-0001-5344-8069), AH(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AI(Max Planck Institute for Astrophysics, Karl-Schwarzschild-Str. 1, D-85748 Garching, Germany), AJ(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia 0000-0001-7801-1410), AK(School of Physics and Astronomy, Monash University, Wellington Rd, Clayton, VIC 3800, Australia 0000-0003-0174-0564), AL(Department of Physics and Kavli Institute for Astrophysics and Space Research, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA 02139, USA), AM(Department of Astronomy, Stockholm University, AlbaNova, Roslagstullbacken 21, SE-10691 Stockholm, Sweden), AN(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia 0000-0003-4932-7699), AO(Research School of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Australian National University, Canberra, ACT 2611, Australia), AP(Max-Planck-Institut für Astronomie, Königstuhl 17, D-69117, Heidelberg, Germany 0000-0001-7671-9140), AQ(Max-Planck-Institut für Astronomie, Königstuhl 17, D-69117, Heidelberg, Germany), AR(Theoretical Astrophysics, Department of Physics and Astronomy, Uppsala University, Box 516 SE-75120 Uppsala, Sweden 0000-0002-3181-3413), AS(Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia &quot;Galileo Galilei&quot; - Università di Padova, Vicolo dell'Osservatorio 3, Padova, IT-35122)</affiliation>
<journal>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Advance Access</journal>
<pubdate>Nov 2020</pubdate>
<keywords type="Astronomy">
<keyword>stars: kinematics and dynamics</keyword>
<keyword>Galaxy: Disc</keyword>
<keyword>Galaxy: formation</keyword>
<keyword>Galaxy: halo</keyword>
<keyword>Galaxy: kinematics and dynamics</keyword>
<keyword>Galaxy: structure</keyword>
</keywords>
<origin>OUP</origin>
<url>http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2020MNRAS.tmp.3219C</url>
<abstract>In this work we combine spectroscopic information from the SkyMapper
survey for Extremely Metal-Poor stars and astrometry from Gaia DR2 to
investigate the kinematics of a sample of 475 stars with a metallicity
range of  $-6.5 \le \rm [Fe/H] \le -2.05$  dex. Exploiting the action
map, we identify 16 and 40 stars dynamically consistent with the Gaia
Sausage and Gaia Sequoia accretion events, respectively. The most
metal-poor of these candidates have metallicities of  $\rm [Fe/H]=-3.31$
 and  $\rm [Fe/H]=-3.74$ , respectively, helping to define the
low-metallicity tail of the progenitors involved in the accretion
events. We also find, consistent with other studies, that ∼21% of
the sample have orbits that remain confined to within 3 kpc of the
Galactic plane, i.e., |Zmax| ≤ 3 kpc. Of particular
interest is a sub-sample (∼11% of the total) of low
|Zmax| stars with low eccentricities and prograde motions.
The lowest metallicity of these stars has [Fe/H] = -4.30 and the
sub-sample is best interpreted as the very low-metallicity tail of the
metal-weak thick disk population. The low |Zmax|, low
eccentricity stars with retrograde orbits are likely accreted, while the
low |Zmax|, high eccentricity pro- and retrograde stars are
plausibly associated with the Gaia Sausage system. We find that a small
fraction of our sample (∼4% of the total) is likely escaping from
the Galaxy, and postulate that these stars have gained energy from
gravitational interactions that occur when infalling dwarf galaxies are
tidally disrupted.</abstract>
<DOI>10.1093/mnras/staa3417</DOI>
</record>

</records>

